- 是突击检查！
- 才不是呢
- Joint raided!
- No!
这只是我们的Raymond，可爱的Shaw中士
That's just our Raymond,
our lovable Sgt. Shaw.
行了玩够了，咱们走，快走！
All right. Let's go, you men.
Come on.
快走！
Let's go.
来吧，中士，Gertrude请你喝啤酒
Come on, Sarge.
Gertrude buy you beer.
这人怎么回事啊？
What's the matter with him?
恐怕我们的圣人Raymond，不懂享受人生
I'm afraid our Saint Raymond,
he don't approve.
或许他在家有女朋友或者未婚妻什么的
Maybe he's got a girl back home,
or something.
他？Raymond？你开玩笑吧？
Him? Our Raymond?
Are you kidding?
- Silvers，这件浴袍怎么样？
- 你说啥？浴袍给我了？快滚
- Silvers, how about the robe?
- What do you mean, my robe? Get out!
情况不妙
Bad here.
- 你怎么知道的？
- Chunjin我就是在前面两英里的地方出生的
- How do you know?
- Chunjin born two miles from here.
自从我们来到朝鲜，到过的每个地方你这个傻逼都说自己是在前面两英里处出生的
So far, every place we've been in Korea,
this joker was born two miles from it.
情况有多坏？
What's so bad about it?
很复杂，周围全是沼泽，三十码深，下面或许还有流沙
Tricky. Swamp all around.
Thirty yards up, maybe quicksand.
没人跟我说过有流沙啊
Nobody said anything about quicksand.
我们不能绕着走吗？
Can't we go around it?
- 不行，中士
- 你有什么建议？
- No, Sergeant.
- What's your personal advice?
接下来二百码，咱们排成一排前进
All walk in single line,
next 200 yards.
不行，排成单排行进不符合战术规范
Rejected. Not tactical
to advance in a single line.
那只能沉进流沙里了
Patrol sink.
我们绕不过去吗？
Can't we go around it?
- 不行，中士
- 不管了
- No, Sergeant.
- Never mind
来吧，传令吧
Okay, pass the word.
“这个国家不会轻易地颁发那枚象征对勇气的最高奖赏的勋章”
“This nation jealously guards its highest award for valor,”
“国会荣耀勋章”
“the Congressional Medal of Honor”
“共有572万人参加了朝鲜战争，”
“In the Korean War, with 5,720,000 personnel engaged,”
“只有77人有幸被授予这枚勋章”
“only 77 men were so honored.”
“这77人之中，就有上士Raymond Shaw”
“One of these 77 men was Staff Sergeant Raymond Shaw.”
“Raymond Shaw离开前线后就直接飞往华盛顿”
“Raymond Shaw was returned from combat and flown to Washington”
“亲自接受由美国总统颁发的勋章”
“to be decorated personally by the President of the United States.”
“这就是为什么他的出现，或者说任何一位荣耀勋章获得者的出现”
“This is why his presence, or that of any Medal of Honor winner,”
“都足以使在场的将军们起立向其敬礼”
“is sufficient to bring generals to their feet, saluting.”
恭喜你，孩子，感觉怎么样？
Congratulations, son. How do you feel?
感觉就像《惊奇科学漫画》里的白痴上尉一样
Like Capt. Idiot
in Astounding Science Comics.
等等，将军
Hold it, General.
将军，请等等，快点，快过来
Hold it, General, please. Come on.
Get in there quickly.
妈妈，这是什么，你在这儿干嘛？
Mother, what is this?
What are you doing here?
Iselin参议员，作为荣耀奖章获得者的父亲你的感觉如何？
Senator Iselin, how does it feel to be
the father of a Medal of Honor winner?
- 他不是我父亲
- 参议员是Raymond的继父
- He is not my father.
- The Senator is Raymond's stepfather.
我只能说，作为...
I can only say that, as one...
一个奉献一生服务国家的人...
who has devoted his life
to the service of his country...
这是你设计好的...
You did this...
你设计好的，妈妈，你组织了这个令人作呕的马戏团
You did this, Mother. You organized
this disgusting three-ring circus.
亲爱的，你可是荣耀奖章的获得者，顺便说一句，恭喜你！
Darling，you're a Medal of Honor winner.
Incidentally, congratulations.
我应该写信告诉你的，但最近几个月家里一团乱
I would have written, but we've been
in a frightful mess the last few months.
好啦，让他过去！
All right, let him through!
够啦够啦，让他过去
That's enough, now.
Let him through.
说‘茄子’
Say 'cheese.'
行了行了，够啦，让这个可怜人过去吧
All right, that's enough, now.
Let the poor boy through.
行行好让他过去吧
Please, let him through.
你怎么啦儿子？我们已经有够多的事忙了...
What is the matter, Raymond?
We've gone to a lot of trouble to...
- 像是给你安排游行
- 游行？
- Arrange the parade for you.
- The parade?
- 把这拿开
- 为什么？你个爱出风头一根筋的傻逼！
- Get that out.
- Why, you publicity-sick, flag-simple goob!
仅仅是因为你的父母和整个国家...
Just because your parents
and the entire country...
- 都为你感到骄傲...
- 骗谁呢，妈妈？
- are proud of you...
- Who's kidding who, Mother?
Johnny已经在11月宣布要准备再次竞选了，你自己很清楚的，不是吗？
Johnny's up for re-election in November.
You've got it all figured out, haven't you?
Johnny Iselin的儿子，荣耀奖章的获得者，这会给你拉大约五万票吧？
Johnny Iselin's boy, Medal of Honor winner
That should get you 50,000 votes.
Raymond，我是你妈，你怎么能这么跟我说话？
Raymond, I'm your mother.
How can you talk to me this way?
我自己什么都不想要
I want nothing for myself.
我的一生都致力于帮助你和Johnny
My entire life is devoted
to helping you and to helping Johnny.
- 我的男子汉们，我的两个小男孩
- 妈，别说了
- My boys, my two little boys.
- Mother, stop it.
你们俩就是我的全部了
That is all I have.
“下午在他抵达华盛顿之后，”
“On the afternoon after his arrival in Washington,”
“Raymond Shaw在白宫受勋...”
“Raymond Shaw was decorated at the White House...”
“美国总统亲自为他佩上勋章”
“by the President of the United States.”
“他的嘉奖令，在由他的指挥官Marco上尉，”
“His citation, attested to by his commanding officer, Captain Marco”
“和侦察队其他九位幸存者证实之后，”
“and the nine surviving members of his patrol,”
“部分内容摘录如下：‘他接受职责的征召，表现英勇，”
“read in part:‘Displaying valor
above and beyond the call of duty,”
“一己之力拯救了侦察队九名队员生命”
“did single-handedly save the lives of nine members of his patrol,”
“端掉敌人的一个机关枪碉堡，”
“capturing an enemy machine-gun nest，”
“并且消灭了一整连的敌军步兵”
“and taking out a full company of enemy infantry.”
“然后他带领这支已经被列入失踪名单长达三天之久的侦察队，”
“He led his patrol, which had been listed as missing in action for three days，”
“穿过敌人的封锁线安全返回’”
“back through the enemy lines to safety.’”
这是“支持Iselin公民委员会”送给他的生日礼物
A gift from the Citizens For Iselin
Committee for his last birthday.
在竞选期间它确实救了我们，你知道吗
It absolutely saved our lives during the campaign，you see.
这个拉出来是双人床
This opens up into a double bed.
这是新闻发布室
This is the Press Room.
这就是我的私人办公室
And this is my private office.
还有什么能消除竞选的痛苦呢？嗯？
Anything to take the pain
out of campaigning, eh?
我经常这么说
That's what I always say.
- 妈，我现在能把军服脱了吗？
- Raymond，你到底怎么了？
- May I take this thing off now, Mother?
- Raymond, what is the matter with you?
你看起来就像头疼的要炸了
You look as if your head were going
to come to a point in seconds.
Johnny，给他杯喝的或者别的什么，坐下，Raymond，放松
Johnny, fix him a drink or something. Sit down, Raymond. Relax.
不用两个半小时咱们就能回家了
We'll be home in less than two-and-a-half hours.
我不和你们回家，妈妈，我要去纽约
I'm not going home with you, Mother. I'm going to New York.
什么？
What?
我在报社找了一份工作
I've got a job on a newspaper.
Holborn Gaines先生的研究助理
Research Assistant to Mr. Holborn Gaines.
Holborn Gaines，那个共产党员？
Holborn Gaines, that Communist?
他不是共产党员，妈妈，事实是，他是个共和党员
He's not a Communist, Mother.
As a matter of fact, he's a Republican.
但他写过很多诋毁Johnny的东西...
But the terrible things he's written
about Johnny...
今天早上他来白宫采访我
He came to interview me
at the White House this morning.
然后我问他能不能给我份工作，他答应了
Afterwards, I asked him for a job.
He gave it to me.
我们发现彼此有很多共同点
We discovered that we had
a great deal in common.
你跟那个可怕的老头能有什么共同点？
What could you possibly have in common
with that dreadful old man?
举个例子吧，我们发现我们都讨厌，鄙视你和Johnny
For one thing, we discovered that we
both loathe and despise you and Johnny.
并且这只是个开始
And that's a beginning.
“朝鲜战争已经结束了”
“The war in Korea was over.”
“Bennett Marco上尉，现在是少校了，被重新分配...”
“Captain, now Major, Bennett Marco had been reassigned”
“到了华盛顿的陆军情报机关工作”
“to Army Intelligence in Washington.”
“大体上说，这是个令人愉快的职位，”
“It was, by and large, a pleasant assignment, ”
“除了一件事，”
“except for one thing.”
“一夜又一夜，少校被同样的噩梦反复折磨着”
“Night after night, the major was plagued by the same reoccurring nightmare.”
停下，停下
Stop it. Stop it.
*&&……*&……&76
￥%……#￥%￥%￥￥%
……&……%……*（）*
*&￥%……%……#￥@#
&……*&（）*&（）&*&
#@@##@￥￥%&……%*
*&（）*&*……&%￥%#￥#
&……*&%#￥#%%……&*
￥……%%￥￥##￥￥…………&
U&^*7^*%^&%$$#
%￥%￥#￥%……&*&*&*&
#@￥%#%…………&*……（）*&）
￥#%￥……%……&*&**（）&*（）
#@！#￥@@#￥￥……&……&*（）……
*&*（）*（）&&…………&――+）+――――
#@%￥……%&*&*（）&（）*
￥#￥#%￥￥#%…………&……&
%￥#￥%￥&%……*……%&……
￥#……%……&……*（）
@#￥%……%&……&*
&……%￥&%￥&……%&*……（）*&（）
请允许我介绍我们的美国来宾
Allow me to introduce
our American visitors.
我必须请求你原谅他们无精打采的态度
I must ask you to forgive their
somewhat lackadaisical manners...
因为我已经调教过他们了，或者说把他们洗过脑了，
but I have conditioned them,
or 'brainwashed' them...
我知道这是个新的单词，
which I understand
is the new American word...
他们相信自己在新泽西的一家酒店的礼堂里...
to believe that they are
in the lobby of a hotel in New Jersey...
正在参加一场女士园艺俱乐部的绣球花讲座
where a meeting of the Ladies'
Garden Club is in progress.
你们应该注意到了我已经告诉他们可以抽烟了
You will notice that I have told them
they may smoke.
我已经允许我的人...
I have allowed my people
to have a little fun...
从选择抽这些奇特的烟草替代品中获得乐趣
in the selection of bizarre tobacco substitutes.
Ed，你抽的开心吗？
Are you enjoying your cigarette, Ed?
是的，太太
Yes, ma'am.
‘抽起来不错，有烟该有的味儿’
‘Tastes good, like a cigarette should.'
现在，同志们...
Now then, comrades...
请让我介绍著名的Raymond Shaw
may I present
the famous Raymond Shaw...
你们飞了8万英里来到满洲里这个沉闷的地方就是为了来看他的
the young man you've flown 80,000 miles
to this dreary spot in Manchuria to see.
Raymond，请你坐到我这边
Raymond, pull your chair over here
by me, please.
我相信你们都听过那个无稽之谈...
I am sure you've all heard
the old wives' tale...
被催眠的对象即使在外界的强迫下...
that no hypnotized
subject may be forced...
也不会做出违背自己道德标准的事，无论什么条件下
to do that which is repellent to his
moral nature, whatever that may be.
当然，这是胡说
Nonsense, of course.
你们做记录的记下来这些，记得要参考Brenman的论文
You note-takers might set down
a reminder to consult Brenman's paper.
对反社会和自我伤害催眠对象的实验
Experiments in the Hypnotic Production of Antisocial and Self-Injurious Behavior
或者Wells 1941年的论文，我觉得是叫...
Or Wells' 1941 paper which was titled,
I believe...
对有前科催眠对象的实验
Experiments in the Hypnotic Production of Crime.
还有，当然，Andrew Salter那本非凡著作，
Or, of course, Andrew Salter's
remarkable book...
条件反射疗法
Conditioned Reflex Therapy
名字就仨字
to name only three.
如果你觉得只有西方世界...
Or if it offends you
that only the West is working...
在制造更多的犯罪和针对现代社会缺陷的罪犯...
to manufacture more crime
and better criminals...
这观点令你觉得不悦...
against the modern shortages...
我推荐 Krasnogorski的
I suggest Krasnogorski's...
主要暴力动机...
Primary violence Motivation...
或者Serov的 对自我毁灭的片面建议
or Serov's The Unilateral Suggestion
to Self-Destruction.
亲爱的Yen先生，你越来越老，也越来越嗦了
My dear Yen, as you grow older,
you grow more long-winded.
你不能赶紧说重点吗？
Can't we get to the point?
这个男人杀过人吗？
Has the man ever killed anyone?
或者没杀过？
Or has he not?
亲爱的Dimitri，我很抱歉
I apologize, my dear Dimitri.
我老是忘了你是农民并且注意力有限
I keep forgetting that you're a young
country and your attention span is limited.
告诉我，Raymond，你杀过人吗？
Tell me, Raymond,
have you ever killed anyone?
- 没有，太太
- 打仗时也没杀过？
- No, ma'am.
- Not even in combat?
打仗时？
In combat?
是的，太太，我觉得杀过
Yes, ma'am, I think so.
你当然杀过，Raymond
Of course you have, Raymond.
Raymond 从小就是一个神枪手
Raymond has been a crack shot
since childhood.
这是他好斗天性的绝佳发泄方法
Marvelous outlet for his aggressions.
能给我把刺刀吗？
May I have the bayonet, please?
别用刀，用手
Not with the knife.
With the hands.
用手？
With the hands?
来，用这个
Here, have him use this.
Raymond，今天，在你团队里你最喜欢谁？
Raymond, whom do you dislike the least
in your group here today?
- 最喜欢？
- 是的
- The least?
- That's right.
我猜是Marco上尉，太太
I guess Capt. Marco, ma'am.
有没有注意到他是如何被权威所吸引的？
Notice how he is always
drawn to authority?
这可不行，Raymond
That won't do, Raymond.
我们需要上尉给你颁发你的勋章
We need the captain
to get you your medal.
还有谁？
Whom else?
- 那就是Ed Mavole了，太太
- 好的
- I guess Ed Mavole, ma'am.
- That's better.
现在，Raymond，拿着这条围巾...
Now then, Raymond,
take this scarf...
勒死Ed Mavole
and strangle Ed Mavole
to death.
好的，太太
Yes, ma'am.
让一下，Ben
Excuse me, Ben.
让一下吧
Pardon me.
嘿，中士，停下
Hey, Sarge, cut it out.
请安静，Ed
Quiet, Ed, please.
现在请你安静地坐好并且配合他
Now, you just sit there quietly
and cooperate.
好的，太太
Yes, ma'am.
少校，据你所知...
Major, to your knowledge...
其他你的侦察队的成员有没有谁做同样的梦？
have any other ex-members of your
patrol had similar dreams?
不，先生，我不知道还有谁也做同样的梦
No, sir, not to my knowledge.
大家有没有对Mavole是行动中死去的两位烈士之一...
Doesn't it strike any one as curious...
这件事感到好奇？
that Mavole was one of the two men
lost in the action?
不过，每晚在我的梦里...
Yet, every night in my dream...
他都被Raymond给...
he's the one that Raymond...
我很抱歉，先生们
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
行了，听着，Marco少校
Now look, Maj. Marco...
自从你第一次告诉我们你那不断重复的噩梦，引起了我们的注意时...
since you first brought this recurring
dream of yours to our attention...
Raymond Shaw，他的妻子，他的背景，他的习惯...
Raymond Shaw, his life,
his background, his habits...
他的朋友和同事就都被仔细地盘查过了
his friends and associates have been
under scrupulous examination.
事实自己会说话，他是清白的
The facts speak for themselves.
他的继父是美国参议员
His stepfather is
a United States senator.
他的母亲是好几个爱国组织的头儿
His mother is head of different
patriotic organizations.
Raymond他本人还是Holborn Gaines最亲密的助理
Raymond himself works as confidential
assistant to Holborn Gaines...
Holborn Gaines可是美国最受人尊重的政治记者
the most respected political journalist in America.
- 真是不可思议...
- Marco少校
- It's inconceivable...
- Major Marco.
我作为精神病咨询专家...
As the consulting
psychiatrist present...
我很有兴趣听听你对Shaw的个人感觉如何
I'd be interested in hearing
your personal feelings about Shaw.
Raymond Shaw是我见过的最友好...
Raymond Shaw is the kindest,
bravest, warmest...
最勇敢，最热情，最完美的人
most wonderful human being
I've ever known in my life.
我知道了
I see.
少校，你是不是一直秉持着这个对他的评价？
And this opinion, Major,
was it generally held?
他的士兵伙伴们，也这么看他吗？
His fellow soldiers, did they feel
the same way toward him?
他们都喜欢他，先生
The men loved him, sir.
怎么会不喜欢呢？他救了他们的命
Why shouldn't they?
He saved their lives.
对我来说很明显嘛，
It would seem obvious to me...
Marco少校正在遭受着...
that Maj. Marco is suffering
a delayed reaction...
对在朝鲜连续战斗18个月的延迟反应
to 18 months of continuous
combat in Korea.
我强烈建议Raymond Shaw的事情就别再讨论了，
I strongly recommend that the matter of
Raymond Shaw be dropped here and now...
然后就暂时分配给Marco少校...
and that Maj. Marco
be temporarily reassigned...
一些更轻松并且，我得说，更不敏感的工作
to less strenuous and, if I may say so,
less sensitive duties.
我觉得在参与几个月的...
I think a few months'
detached service...
像是，公共关系工作后...
to, perhaps, the Public
Relations Corps...
少校应该就会恢复健康了
should put the Major right
back in the pink.
部长先生...
Mr. Secretary...
部长先生，你能向我们解释一下预算削减的提案吗？
Mr. Secretary, can you explain
the proposed cut in budget?
先生，你既然问了一个直接的问题
Since, sir, you've asked
a simple-minded question...
我就给你一个直接的答案
I will give you an equally
simple-minded answer.
当今世界没有能威胁到自由世界的海军力量了...
Since no great naval power
menaces the free world today...
所以海军舰艇数量的压倒性优势似乎已经是没有必要了
the Navy's overwhelming preponderance
of surface ships seems to be superfluous.
所以我们要削减预算
Hence the cut in budget.
少校，我的时间很宝贵
Major, my time is important.
咱们还得在这儿说多久的废话？
How much longer must we go on
with this nonsense?
如果没有更多的问题，那采访可以结束了
If there are no further questions,
I think that about wraps things up.
部长先生，我还有问题，先生
Mr. Secretary,
I have a question, sir.
先生，你是谁？
Who are you, sir?
我是美国参议员John Yerkes Iselin
I am United States Senator
John Yerkes Iselin.
我有个严肃的问题...
And I have a question so serious...
我们的国家安全或许就取决于你的答案
that the safety of our nation may well
depend on your answer.
你谁？
Who?
别回避我的问题，部长先生，别回避
No evasions, Mr. Secretary,
no evasions, if you please, sir.
回避？你在说什么？
Evasions? What the hell
are you talking about?
这是个什么？傻逼吗？
What kind of foolishness is this?
部长先生，我是个新手，但我不觉得...
I'm new at this job, but I don't
think it's good public relations...
这样跟一个参议员说话会有利于公共关系发展，即使他是个傻逼
to talk that way to a senator,
even if he is an idiot.
我是美国参议员John Yerkes Iselin...
I am United States Senator
John Yerkes Iselin...
并且我手里有一份列有270个人名的名单...
and I have here a list
of the names of 270 persons...
这207个人我们的国防部长都认识...
who are known
by the Secretary of Defense...
并且他们都是共产党...
as being members of
the Communist Party...
并且这个人还在为国防部工作...
and who are still, nevertheless,
working at shaping the policy...
居然，仍然在为我们的国家制定国防政策！
of the Defense Department!
- 你是谁？
- 我要求答案
- Senator who?
- I demand an answer.
先生，你什么都掩盖不了
There will be no covering up, sir.
- 什么？
- 你什么都掩盖不了
- What?
- No covering up.
- 你是不会得到这份名单的
- 你是怎么混进来的？
- You won't get your hands on this list.
- How did you get in here in the first place?
- 少校，把这个疯子扔出去
- 并且我郑重地...
- Major, throw that lunatic out of here.
- And I deeply regret having to say...
- 面对着在场的女士们和先生们...
- 你自称是参议员？
- in front of these ladies and gentlemen...
- You claim to be a senator?
还有我们伟大的国家里所有的听众们观众们，对你说，你已经失去了我的信任
...and the radio audience of our great nation
that you no longer have my confidence.
你是个傻逼，你疯了
You're an idiot, if you ask me.
You're out of your mind.
这已经不是国防部内部调查就能解决的事了
This is no longer a matter for investigation
by the Defense Department.
滚出去！
Get out of here!
- 我恐怕你已经没有机会了
- 来人把他拉出去
- I'm afraid you've lost your chance.
- Get that man out of this room.
这件事已经由美国参议院负责了
This matter is now the responsibility
of the United States Senate.
我不想让他呆在这儿，听到了吗？把他带走！
I will not have him in here,
do you hear me? Not ever!
如果我再在这个房间里看见你，我会亲自把你扔出去
If I ever catch you in this room again,
I'll throw you out bodily.
你还想干什么？滚
What do you want?
Get out of here.
- 等一下
- 你别再拍了！
- Hold it.
- Don't you take my picture anymore.
把人都赶走！
Clear this room!
Iselin参议员，我想核实一下你说的数字
Sen. Iselin.
I'd like to verify that number, sir.
你说有多少共产党员？
How many Communists did you say?
确切地说...
I said there are exactly...
我有证据表明...
I have proof there are...
在国防部里有104个正式的共产党员
104 card-carrying Communists
in the Defense Department.
多少，先生？
How many, sir?
275，我现在只能说这么多了
275, and that's all I have to say
on the subject at this time.
少校，他说有多少？
Major, how many did he say?
抱歉等一会儿
Excuse me just a moment.
少校，他说有多少？
Major, how many did he say?
- 很好，Raymond
- 谢谢，太太
- Very good, Raymond.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Marco上尉？
- 在
- Capt. Marco?
- Yes.
请站起来上尉
On your feet, Captain, please.
抱歉，太太
Sorry, ma'am.
上尉，当你和你的侦察队返回朝鲜时...
Captain，when you are returned
with your patrol to Korea...
你去司令部...
and you make your way
to Command Headquarters...
要做的第一件事是什么？
what will be the first duty
you will undertake?
太太，我会汇报巡逻情况
I will make my report
on the patrol, ma'am.
你会汇报什么？
What will you report?
我会立马推荐...
I will recommend urgently...
Raymond Shaw，请求授予他最高荣耀勋章
that Raymond Shaw be posted
for the Medal of Honor.
他救了我们的命并且消灭了一整个连的中国步兵
He saved our lives and took out
a complete company of Chinese infantry.
一整个连？这什么意思？
A complete company?
What the hell is this?
我们可以为这个特别的计划省下一个虚构的步兵连...
We can spare an imaginary company
of infantry for this particular plan...
- Mikhail Mikhailovich
- 好吧
- Mikhail Mikhailovich.
- All right.
如果，我们要在全世界的报纸上...
If we are out to humiliate
our brave Chinese ally...
羞辱我们的英勇的中国同盟...
in the newspapers of the world...
我们应该写他歼灭了一个营
we might as well make it
a full battalion.
我们不反对，同志，我向你保证
We don't object, Comrade,
I assure you of that.
不过，同志，我们也谢谢你用这种眼光考虑这件事
However, Comrade, we thank you for
thinking of the matter in that light.
我们能继续示范了吗？
If we may proceed
with the demonstration...
这个坐在上尉旁边的人是谁？
who is that little fellow
sitting next to the Captain?
是Bobby Lembeck...
That's Bobby Lembeck...
我觉得你会叫他，我们的吉祥物
our mascot, I guess you'd call him.
看起来还没到能参加你们军队的年龄
Doesn't look old enough
to be in your army.
我猜也是，但他已经入伍了，太太
I guess he isn't, but there he is, ma'am.
Marco上尉，能请你好心把你的枪借给Raymond吗？
Capt. Marco, will you be good enough
to lend Raymond your pistol, please?
好的，太太
Yes, ma'am.
- 谢谢，Ben
- 没事儿孩子
- Thanks, Ben.
- Sure, kid.
向Bobby开枪，Raymond
Shoot Bobby, Raymond.
打他的前额
Through the forehead.
醒醒，没事了
Wake up, it's all right.
没事了
Everything's all right.
放心吧，没事了
It's all right.
又是同一个梦？
That same dream again?
更糟糕的是...
What makes it so awful...
不断地梦着Shaw中士干那些事
is to keep dreaming a thing
like that about Sgt. Shaw.
已经连着几个周都做这个梦了
It's been going on for weeks, now.
我一定是要疯了
I must be going crazy.
你应该给Shaw中士写封信
You ought to write to Sgt. Shaw.
- 我跟你说了我没事
- 问问是不是还有别人也做同样的梦
- I tell you, nothing's wrong with me.
- Ask if anyone else is having similar dreams.
或许我会写
Maybe I will.
或许我会写的
Maybe I'll do that.
如果有人能帮助我，那只有他了
If anybody can help me, he can.
你很喜欢他不是吗？
You like him a lot, don't you?
Raymond Shaw是我见过的...
Raymond Shaw is the bravest,
kindest, warmest...
最友好，最勇敢，最热情，最完美的人
most wonderful human being
I've ever known in my life.
亲爱的中士，我不得不把这件事说出了，或者把这件事写给别人
Dear Sarge，I had to say this or write this
to someone
因为我觉得我要疯了
because I think I'm going nuts.
由于你是我在军队里最好的朋友，所以我告诉你
And since you were
my best friend in the Army, here goes.
中士，我有麻烦了
Sarge, I'm in trouble.
我不敢睡觉因为我会做噩梦
I'm afraid to go to sleep
because I have terrible dreams.
我梦到了你获得勋章时所在的那支侦察队里的所有成员
I dream about all the guys on the patrol
where you won the medal
并且梦里还有很多中国人
and the dream has
a lot of Chinese people in it,
还有不少俄罗斯军队的高级领导人
and a lot of big brass
from the Russian Army.
这只是大体的描述，你一定得相信我的话
Well, it's pretty rough,
you have to take my word for that.
- 请接Raymond Shaw
- 我就是
- Raymond Shaw, please.
- This is he.
Raymond，你怎么不玩玩单人纸牌消遣消遣呢？
Raymond, Why don't you pass the time
by playing a little solitaire?
- 看到方块皇后了吗？
- 是的，先生
- Can you see the red queen?
- Yes, sir.
很好
Good.
下个周六，你会在...
One week from next Saturday,
you will be called for
上午11:10分接到一通电话，然后会带你去
Timothy Swardon疗养院
at 11:10 a.m. and taken to the Timothy Swardon
Sanitarium,
在61大街东84号
84 East 61st Street.
我们想让你在那儿做个体检，
你清楚吗？
We want you there for a checkup.
Is that clear?
你可以把牌收起来了，再见，Raymond
You may put the cards away now.
Goodbye, Raymond.
Gaines先生，是Shaw先生，出事了
Mr. Gaines, it's Mr. Shaw.
他出车祸了，肇事司机跑了
He was run down on the street
by a hit-and-run driver.
美联社发的消息，
It just came over the AP.
天啊
Good heavens.
查查他在哪个医院，给他们打电话
Find out what hospital he's in,
and call them.
看看咱们能不能帮上什么忙
See if there's anything
we can do to help.
你太客气了，再见
You're welcome. Goodbye.
是Gaines先生从他的报社打来的
That was Mr. Gaines,
from his newspaper.
他说要Raymond安心休息，什么也别担心
He said to tell him to take it easy
and not to worry about a thing.
当然，咱们不能告诉他
Which, of course,
we will not tell him...
这事故是早就秘密安排好的
on the chance it is
some sort of pre-arranged code.
- Zilkov同志？
- 是，什么事？
- Comrade zilkov?
- Yes?
我是Yen Lo，Pavlov学院的
Yen Lo. Pavlov Institute.
博士...
Doctor...
见到你特别荣幸
an honor and a pleasure.
你们可以走了
You may go.
你什么时候到的？
When did you arrive?
我昨晚通过使馆配额飞过来的
I was flown in last night
under embassy quota.
一趟令人作呕的旅程
Revolting journey.
Raymond，很高兴能再次见到你
Raymond, it's nice to see you again.
先生，我也很高兴再次见到你
It's nice to see you again, sir.
我们布置的这个精细的现场
We're going through
this elaborate procedure...
只是个预防措施
simply out of precaution...
预防万一有人来访
in case there are any visitors.
尽管我想不出来谁会来看望他
Although I cannot imagine
who will visit Raymond.
- 你这个地方不错啊
- 谢谢，博士
- Attractive plant you have here.
- Thank you, Doctor.
其实这里只是那些有钱酒鬼的疗养院
It's actually a rest home
for wealthy alcoholics.
三年前我们就把这地方盘下来了
We were able to purchase it
three years ago.
除了这一层和上面那层出于安全原因封闭了
Except for this floor and the floor above it,
which is sealed for security purposes...
其他的都照常使用
the rest functions quite normally.
这里是苏联在美国的据点之一
It is one of the few Soviet
operations in America...
实际上在上个财年这个据点还盈利了
that actually showed a profit
at the end of the last fiscal year.
盈利？财年？
Profit? Fiscal year?
当心，我亲爱的Zilkov，资本主义可是传染性极高的病毒
Beware, my dear Zilkov.
The virus of capitalism's highly infectious.
很快你就会往外放贷了
Soon, you'll be lending money out
at interest.
Zilkov同志，你一定得试着培养幽默感
You must try, Comrade Zilkov,
to cultivate a sense of humor.
没有什么比笑一笑能更好地减轻一天的烦恼了
There is nothing like a good laugh
to lighten the burdens o the day.
告诉我，Raymond...
Tell me, Raymond...
你还记得自己谋杀了Mavole 和 Lembeck吗?
do you remember murdering
Mavole and Lembeck?
你能再说一遍吗？先生？
I beg your pardon, sir?
Mavole 和 Lembeck
Mavole and Lembeck...
侦察队的那两位烈士
the men who were lost
on the patrol.
你能记起来他们发生了什么事吗？
Do you recall
what happened to them?
那是一次目标明确的夜晚行动
It was a very clear action
for a night action.
Marco上尉发射了几个低空信号弹
Capt. Marco sent up
some low flares...
所以能很清楚地看到发生了什么
so it was easy to see
what was happening.
Bobby Lembeck被分割到了左边
Bobby Lembeck got separated
to the left.
Mavole跟在他的后面
Mavole went after him.
当他跟上Bobby时敌人已经确定了他们的位置
By the time he reached him,
the enemy had a fix on the position.
他们立刻就被一发迫击炮弹炸死了
They were killed instantly
by a high mortar shell.
我觉得他们都不知道被什么打中了
I don't think they ever knew
what hit them.
同志，你能明白...
Do you realize, Comrade...
任你支配的武器的意义吗？
the implications of the weapon
that has been placed at your disposal?
Raymond，你可以摘掉头上的绷带了
You may remove
your head bandage, Raymond.
一个正常的，接受过正规教育的美国人
A normally conditioned
American...
被培养成一个杀手，并且对自己杀人这件事没有一点记忆
who has been trained to kill and then
to have no memory of having killed.
没有记忆，他就不会有负罪感
Without memory of his deed,
he cannot possibly feel guilt.
当然，他也没有任何理由害怕自己被抓
Nor will he, of course, have any
reason to fear being caught.
在减轻了那些美国特有的负罪感和害怕的症状后，
Having been relieved of those uniquely
American symptoms guilt and fear...
他就不可能泄密了
he can not possibly give himself away.
我们的Raymond表面上还会是那个正常的，有用的，
Our Raymond will remain
an outwardly normal, productive...
头脑清醒的，被社会尊重的人
sober and respected member
of the community.
我得说，如果咱们使用得当，警察也抓不住他
And, I should say, if properly used,
entirely police-proof.
他不单单是被洗脑了，应该说是被干洗了
His brain has not only been washed,
as they say, it has been dry-cleaned.
谢谢你，Raymond，你可以把绷带戴回去了
Thank you, Raymond,
you may replace your head bandage.
不管这层封不封闭，你都得允许访客来...
Sealed floors or no, you
will permit him visitors...
防止别人起疑
to avoid suspicion.
我的一支专家团队今晚就会飞过来
A team of my specialists
is being flown in tonight.
彻底检查他的机能，记得在探望时间的间隔工作
It will take about a week,
working between visiting hours...
得花上大约一个周的时间
to check the mechanism out
completely.
毕竟把他催眠已经是两年前的事了
It has been two years since
the conditioning took place.
在把他交给美国的操纵者之前...
And you want to be sure the linkages
are still functioning correctly...
必须确定所有的连接都还运转正常
before he is turned over
to his American operator.
- 同志，我得走了
- 你要去哪儿？
- Comrade, if you will excuse me.
- Where are you going?
既然在我的专家们来之前我没啥可干的...
Since I can do nothing more
until my specialists arrive...
我想去梅西百货逛一下午
I had thought to spend
the afternoon at Macy's.
我夫人可是给了我一张可怕至极的购物清单
Madame Yen has given me
the most appalling list.
不，不，我以个人名义担保，他已经准备好被交回给美国操控者了
No，no. I personally guarantee it. He is ready to be
turned over to his American operator.
我作为苏维埃在
And I, being personally responsible
for Soviet Security...
美国东海岸的负责人
in the entire Eastern Seaboard
of the United States...
拒绝把他交回他的操纵者手上
refuse to turn him over
to his operator...
除非，至少进行一次实地检测
until at least one practical test
has been run.
你说这个男人被培养成了刺客
You say the man has been built
as an assassin.
好啊，那么，让他暗杀个人吧
Very well, then.
Let him assassinate someone.
你这样一个肩负重大责任的安全官员...
I'm shocked that a security officer
with the responsibility you hold...
会出于纯粹的紧张而让如此有用的Raymond...
would risk a mechanism
as valuable as Raymond...
冒这么大的风险，真让我感到惊讶
out of sheer nervousness.
你自己也承认他已经两年多没杀人了
You yourself admit the man has not
killed for over two years.
我向你保证，博士，我会把风险降到最低
I assure you, Doctor, conditions
offering minimum risk can be arranged.
好吧，如果你坚持干这傻事...
All right.
If you insist on this foolishness...
就让他在封闭楼层杀一个你的手下吧
have him kill one of your own people
here on a sealed floor.
我很乐意
I would gladly.
但现在我们的人员搭配恰好处于一个运转流畅的状态
But our table of organization happens to be
under acceptable strength as it is.
为什么我们不能理性地干这事？
Why can't we be reasonable
about this?
为什么他不能去外面杀个没用的人？
Why can't he kill some
non-productive person on the outside?
那好吧...
Very well, then.
不过为了保护他，必须给他下令，
For his own protection, he must be
instructed that if he is ever...
如果他在暗杀现场被发现，
discovered at the scene of an
assignment, this other person...
那他必须杀掉发现他的人或人们
or persons must also be killed.
好的，博士，你觉得他应该杀谁?
All right, doctor.
Whom do you think he should kill?
要有幽默感，亲爱的Zilkov，时时刻刻都要有幽默感
With humor, my dear Zilkov,
always with a little humor.
如果我们要杀，为了一个更好的纽约，就杀...
If kill we must, for a better New York,
why should it not be...
他的报社老板吧
Holborn Gaines先生？
his superior at the newspaper,
Mr. Holborn Gaines?
杀了他...
With Mr. Gaines out of the way...
Raymond不就可以升职了吗？
might he not then be given
that very influential job himself?
是谁？
是我，Gaines先生
Who's there?
It's me, Mr. Gaines.
是我，Gaines先生
Raymond
Raymond.
很抱歉打扰你，先生
I'm sorry to disturb you, sir.
别对我这件长得荒唐的睡衣有什么傻傻的想法
Don't get any silly ideas about
this ridiculous-looking bed jacket.
这是我妻子的，这是全家最暖和的衣服了
It was my wife's.
It's the warmest thing I have.
晚上穿着在床上看书最好了
Perfect for reading
in bed at night.
我不知道你已经结婚了，先生
I didn't know
you were married, sir.
她六年前死了
She died nearly six years ago.
你凌晨四点来这儿干嘛啊？
What the devil are you doing here
at 4 a.m.
你不是应该在医院的吗？
Anyway, I thought you were
in the hospital.
别告诉我你这么早来就是为了聊聊
Don't tell me you've come here at
this ridiculous hour to talk something over.
你不会是过来掏心窝子告诉我你那风流韵事的细节的吧？
You're not going to pour out your heart with
the details of a sordid love affair, are you?
事实上，他们告诉我你应该已经睡了
As a matter of fact,
they told me you'd be asleep.
- 谁说的?
- 他们
- Who told you I'd be asleep?
- They did.
他们？
They?
Who are 'they'?
这神秘的“他们”是谁？
Who's this mysterious 'they'?
回答我，孩子
Answer me, my boy.
- 上校
- Ben
- Colonel.
- Ben.
- 我能进来一会儿吗？
- 请进
- May I come in for a minute?
- Please do. Come on in.
我问你两个问题，上校，A,这是个正式的访问吗？B，我给你调杯喝的?
May I ask you，Colonel. A Is this an official visit?
And B May I mix you a drink?
A，是个正式访问，B，调吧
A Yes, it is,
and B You certainly may.
- 威士忌行吗？
- 行
- Scotch all right?
- Fine.
天啊，你从哪里弄的这么多书？
My God, where do you
get all the books?
我一个兰登书屋的朋友给我的
I got a guy who picks them out for me,
at random.
加水？
Water all right?
行
Fine.
他在三藩市...
He's in San Francisco.
有个小书店
Got a little bookstore out there...
并且我无论驻扎在那儿他都给我寄书
and he ships them to me
wherever I happen to be stationed.
- 你都读过？
- 是的
- You read them all?
- Yeah.
它们确实能帮我在敌人进攻时放松自己
They'd also make great insulation
against an enemy attack.
实际上我只是有兴趣读罢了，你知道吗
But the truth of the matter is
that I'm just interested in，you know.
像是《现代银行原理》
Principles of Modern Banking
《海盗史》
The History of Piracy
《奥罗斯科画集》
The Paintings of Orozco,
《法国现代戏剧》
Modern French Theater
《黑手党管理的法理因素》
The Jurisprudential Factor
of Mafia Administration,
《马的疾病》还有Joyce Cary的小说还有
Diseases of Horses
and the novels of Joyce Cary and
《阿拉伯人的民族选择》，之类的
Ethnic Choices of the Arabs
Things like that
- Ben？
- 先生？
- Ben?
- Sir？
军队里有很多事是错的...
The army's got a lot of things
wrong with it...
但它确实照顾自己人，这就是我来这里的原因
but it does take care of its own people,
which is why I'm here.
作为一个公共关系官员，你很失职
As a public relations officer,
you're a disaster.
- 我从没想过干这个工作...
- 不说别的了...
- I never wanted the job..
- Apparently, among other things...
就说你让部长对着那个让他暴跳如雷的傻缺Iselin...
you permitted the Secretary to make some
unfortunate remarks to that idiot Iselin...
- 说了很多不和时宜的话这件事吧
- Mickey，请听我说
- which started him off on a rampage.
- Mickey, listen to me, please.
六个月以来，一个不断重复的梦快要把我逼疯了...
For six months, I've been driven nearly mad
by a recurring dream...
主管的卫生官员会...
The medical officer in charge...
卫生官员怎么会懂情报工作？
What the hell does the Medical Corps
know about intelligence work, Milt?
告诉你吧，有些事很假，
I tell you,
there's something phony going on.
关于我，Raymond Shaw，还有勋章的事，
There's something phony about me,
Raymond Shaw...
有很多疑点
about the whole Medal of Honor
business.
举个例子吧，当那个精神病专家问我我对
Raymond的个人看法，
For instance, when the psychiatrist asked
me how I personally felt about Raymond...
还有整个侦察队对他的看法时，你听见我是怎么说的吗？
and how the whole patrol felt about him,
did you hear what I said?
你还记得吗？
Did you really hear what I said?
我说：“Raymond Shaw...
I said, 'Raymond Shaw
is the kindest, warmest...
是我见过的最友好，最热情，最勇敢
最完美的人”
'bravest, most wonderful human
being I have ever known.'
此时此刻，我依然这么认为，
And even now I feel that way,
this minute.
但是我脑海中有个声音告诉我，这不是真的
Yet, somewhere in the back of my mind,
something tells me it's not true.
这不是我的看法
It's just not true.
Raymond不是不讨人喜欢，
It isn't as if Raymond's hard to like.
而是根本不可能会有人喜欢他！
He's impossible to like!
他或许是我见到过的...
He's probably one of
the most repulsive human beings...
最讨厌的人
I've known in all of my life.
Ben，我就是来告诉你公共关系部不要你了
Ben, what I came to tell you is
Public Relations has sent you back to me.
以你现在的状态，我也没法给你分配工作
And in your present state
there's no possible way I can use you.
现在，我给你无限期的病假
As of this moment,
I'm placing you on indefinite sick leave.
Ben，出门放松放松吧，找个姑娘，在太阳底下躺躺
Go away, Ben. Find yourself a girl.
Lie in the sun.
我的回答必然是拒绝
I absolutely refuse.
你没明白
You don't seem to understand.
少校，我刚刚给你的不是建议
What I've just told you
is not a suggestion, Major.
而是命令
It is an order.
好吧，长官
Yes, sir.
晚安，Ben
Good night, Ben.
- 介意我抽烟吗？
- 没事，抽吧
- Do you mind if I smoke?
- Not at all. Please do.
马里兰州很美
Maryland's a beautiful state.
- 这里是特拉华州
- 我知道
- This is Delaware.
- I know.
我当年参与过这条铁路的铺设工程
I was one of the original Chinese workmen
who laid the track on this stretch.
不管怎么说，马里兰州还是很美
But, nonetheless,
Maryland is a beautiful state.
还有俄亥俄州，也很美
So is Ohio, for that matter.
我猜也是，哥伦布是个有名的足球城
I guess so. Columbus is
a tremendous football town.
- 你是干铁路这行儿的？
- 不干了
- You in the railroad business?
- Not anymore.
不过，请让我指出一个问题...
However, if you will permit me
to point out...
你应该问我，
when you ask that question,
you should say...
“你是干铁路线建设的？”
'Are you in the railroad line? '
你哪儿人？
Where's your home?
我来自军队，我是个少校
I'm in the army. I'm a Major.
我大半辈子都在军队里度过
I've been in the army most of my life.
经常要开拔到不同的地方
We move a good deal.
我出生在新罕布什尔州
I was born in New Hampshire.
我曾在那儿的弗朗西斯湖露过一次营
I went to a girls' camp once
on Lake Francis.
那可是很往北的地方
That's pretty far north.
- 你叫什么？
- Euginie
- What's your name?
- Euginie.
再说一遍？
Pardon?
没开玩笑，我真叫这个
No kidding, I really mean it.
是个法语名，英语发音就成男名了
Crazy French pronunciation
and all.
- 挺好听的
- 谢谢
- It's pretty.
- Thank you.
我猜你的朋友们叫你Jennie吧？
I guess your friends
call you Jennie?
没这么叫过，我很希望他们能这么叫
Not yet, they haven't,
for which I am deeply grateful.
但你可以叫我Jennie
But you may call me Jennie.
你朋友们叫你什么？
What do your friends call you?
Rosie
Rosie.
为什么？
Why?
我全名是Eugenie Rose
My full name is Eugenie Rose.
这两个名字里，我更喜欢Rosie
Of the two names,
I've always favored Rosie...
因为读起来有棕香皂和啤酒的味道
because it smells of brown soap
and beer.
Eugenie读起来太脆弱了
Eugenie is somehow more fragile.
我刚才问你名字时，你说你叫Eugenie
When I asked you what your name was,
you said it was Eugenie.
可能当时我或多或少感觉有些脆弱吧
It's quite possible I was feeling
more or less fragile at that instant.
我一直不明白“或多或少”是什么意思
I could never figure out what that
phrase meant 'more or less.'
- 你是阿拉伯人？
- 不是
- Are you Arabic?
- No.
我叫Ben，实际上应该是Bennett
My name is Ben. It's really Bennett.
我父亲用Arnold Bennett的名字给我取名
I was named after Arnold Bennett.
- 那个作家？
- 不，是个中校
- The writer?
- No. A lieutenant colonel.
当时是我父亲的指挥官
He was my father's commanding officer
at the time.
- 你姓什么？
- Marco
- What's your last name?
- Marco.
Marco少校
Maj. Marco.
- 你是阿拉伯人？
- 不是
- Are you Arabic?
- No.
我换个问法吧
Let me put it another way.
你结婚了吗？
Are you married?
- 没有，你呢？
- 没有
- No. You?
- No.
- 你姓什么？
- Cheney
- What's your last name?
- Cheney.
我是一个叫Justin的人的制片助理
I'm production assistant
for a man named Justin...
他上一季有过两次演出
who had two hits last season.
我住在54大街...
I live on 54th Street...
离着现代艺术博物馆很近
a few doors from
the Modern Museum of Art...
我是那儿的特权饮茶会员，不加奶油
of which I am a Tea-Privileges Member.
No cream.
我住在54大街西53号
I live at 53 West 54th Street.
3B号公寓
Apartment 3 B.
记得住吗？
Can you remember that?
黄金国59970，我的电话
Eldorado 59970.
记得住吗？
Can you remember that?
你驻扎在纽约？
Are you stationed in New York?
“驻扎”这个词用得对吗？
Or is stationed the right word?
不是纽约，我驻扎在华盛顿
I'm not exactly stationed in New York.
I was stationed in Washington.
但我病了，现在在休假，我要去纽约玩
But I got sick, and now I'm on leave
and I'm going to spend it in New York.
黄金国59970
Eldorado 59970.
我要去看我的一个朋友，他是个记者
I'm going to look up an old friend of mine
who's a newspaper man.
我们一起参加了朝鲜战争
We were in Korea together.
Shaw先生，外面有人想见你
Mr. Shaw, there's a gentleman outside
to see you.
- 谁？
- 是个东方人，先生
- A gentleman?
- An Oriental gentleman, sir.
他说他是你的战友
He said he was in the army with you.
我不记得我有东方人战友
There were no Oriental gentlemen
in the army with me.
他坚持要见你，先生，特别坚持
He is very insistent, sir.
好吧，让他进来吧
All right, show him in.
我是春锦，Shaw先生，长官
I am Chunjin, Mr. Shaw, sir.
我当时是52团查理连队的翻译
I was interpreter attached
to Charlie Company, 52nd Regiment.
是，我想起来了
Yes, I remember you.
你是侦察队的向导兼翻译
You were the guide and interpreter
to the patrol.
我能为你做点什么？
What can I do for you?
- 我是说，你来这儿干什么？
- 你父亲没跟你说吗？
- I mean， what are you doing here?
- Your father did not say to you?
- 我父亲？
- 是的，Iselin参议员，我给他写...
- My father?
- Yes. Sen. Iselin. I write to...
他不是我父亲
Sen. Iselin is not my father.
我再重复一遍，他不是我父亲
Repeat, he is not my father.
如果你来美国这一趟什么也没学到，
那就把这个事实记住吧
If you learn nothing else on your visit
to this country, memorize that fact.
我给Iselin参议员写了信
I write to Sen. Iselin.
我告诉他我曾是你们侦察队的翻译
I tell him how I interpret
your outfit.
我跟他说我想来美国，他给我办了签证
I tell him I want to come to America.
He get me visa.
现在我需要一份工作
Now I need job.
工作？
A job?
是的，长官，Shaw先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Shaw.
但是亲爱的朋友，我们这儿不需要翻译
But, my dear fellow,
we don't need interpreters here.
在美国大家都说英语，要韩语翻译干嘛
We all speak the same language.
我是个裁缝，我会修东西
我是个厨师，我会开车
I am tailor and mender.
I am cook, I drive car.
我是个清洁工，洗碗工，我什么都能修，
我能帮你收信回信
I am cleaner and scrubber.
I fix anything. I take message.
我住我表哥家
I sleep at house of my cousin.
我来你这儿找工作...
I ask for job with you...
是因为我知道你是那个救了我的命的好人
because you are a great man
who saved my life.
我觉得我会需要一个贴身男仆
I could use a valet, I think.
并且还想要个厨子，我强调一下，
得是个好厨子
And I would like having a cook.
A good cook, I mean.
好的，你可以住你表哥家
Very well, you can live at your cousin's.
我每周付你60刀
I will pay you $ 60 a week.
你可以每个周四和隔周周日休息
You will have every Thursday
and every other Sunday off.
谢谢你，Shaw先生
Thank you, Mr. Shaw.
我过会儿要去华盛顿
I'm leaving for Washington
in a few minutes.
晚上8:10分回来，希望桌上会有坐好的晚餐等着我
I'll be back here by 8:10 p.m.
I would like to have dinner waiting.
好的长官，Shaw先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Shaw.
晚饭会像在军队那时一样
Just like United States Army.
哦，上帝啊，别
Oh, God, I hope not.
你今天下午一定会有非凡的表现的，亲爱的..
You're going to be marvelous
in there this afternoon, hon...
我知道你会的
ljust know you are.
只有一件事儿还困扰着我，宝贝儿
There's just one thing, babe.
如果我们能把国防部里的共产党人数...
I'd be a lot happier if we could just
settle on the number...
确定下来，我会更高兴的
of Communists I know there are
in the Defense Department.
我是说，你总是把这个数字变来变去...
I mean, the way you keep changing
the figures on me all the time...
这让我看上去像个疯子，像个白痴
it makes me look like
some kind of a nut, an idiot.
甚至还有人拿这个开我玩笑
The boys were even starting
to kid me about it.
就昨天，在衣帽间，他们说：“嘿，Johnny...”
Just yesterday in the cloakroom,
they said, 'Hey, Johnny'...
如果你出尔反尔，那你会像个更大的傻瓜
You'll look like an even bigger idiot
if you don't get in there and do exactly what you're told
整个美国的报纸都在报道谁？都在讨论什么？
Who are they writing about all over
this country, and what are they saying?
他们写的是：“国防部里有共产党吗?”
是吗？
Are they saying, 'Are there any
Communists in the Defense Department? '
当然不是，他们写的是...
Of course not.
They're saying...
“国防部里有多少共产党？”
'How many Communists
are there in the Defense Department? '
所以别突然装的像很有经验似的说话...
So stop talking like an expert
all of a sudden...
坐好你该做的，出去说你应该说的，
就行了
and get out there and
say what you're supposed to say.
别这样，宝贝儿
Come on, babe.
我很抱歉，亲爱的
I'm sorry, hon.
如果我们把数字定下来会对你有帮助吗？
Would it really make it easier for you
if we settled on just one number?
一个确定的简单的数字最好了，
我还好记
Just one real simple number
that will be easy for me to remember.
现在，在国防部里...
There are exactly
57 card-carrying members...
确切地说，有57名正式的共产党员
of the Communist Party in
the Department of Defense at this time.
演讲者请注意议事程序
Point of order, Mr. Speaker.
Raymond到底做了什么事？
What was Raymond doing
with his hands?
那些老太太是怎么变成俄罗斯人的？
How did the old ladies
turn into Russians?
Raymond到底做了什么事？
What was Raymond doing
with his hands?
那些老太太是怎么变成俄罗斯人的？
Raymond到底做了什么事？
How did the old ladies turn into Russians?
What was Raymond doing with his hands?
你在这儿干嘛？
What were you doing there?
Raymond到底做了什么事？
What was Raymond doing
with his hands?
你在这儿干嘛？
What were you doing there?
我得说，你让警察局的人打电话给我，约我出来，
It was original of you to have
the police department call so shyly...
这个方式很新颖，也显得你很害羞
and ask for our first date.
他们问我想打给谁...
They asked me who
I'd be willing to...
我知道，谢谢你，非常感谢
I know, and thank you，thank you very much.
我得去找Raymond，说不定他现在在家
I've got to find Raymond.
Maybe he's home by now.
好的，亲爱的，你想干嘛都行
All right, darling.
Whatever you want.
但首先，我得告诉你点事
But first, I have something to tell you.
你知道在你聪明地利用警察约我的时候，
我在干嘛吗？
You know what I was doing
when you so cleverly had the police call?
别猜了，你太累了
Don't bother trying to guess,
you're too tired.
我直接告诉你吧
I'll tell you what I was doing.
在我下车之后...
After I dropped you off...
我就直接往家走，然后我上楼...
I went straight home,
and when I got upstairs...
- 3B号公寓
- 是的，很好
- Apartment 3 B.
- That's right. Very good.
在我脱下大衣之前，我给我的未婚夫打了电话
Before I even took my coat off,
I telephoned my fiance
我跟你说了我没结婚
但我没说我没订婚
I told you I wasn't married,
I never said I wasn't engaged.
继续，我给他打了电话，
Well, I called up my fiance
and he came over as soon as he could...
他飞快地赶来了...
which was instantly...
然后我告诉他，我遇见了你...
and I told him
I had just met you...
然后我把戒指还给了他
and I gave him his ring back.
我试着告诉他，我对我可能给他造成的痛苦，
表示遗憾
I tried to convey my regrets for
whatever pain I might be causing him.
这时，警察打来了，说你邀请我去第24分局见你
Just then, you had the police call to invite
me to meet you at the 24th Precinct.
所以我抓起大衣，亲了我的未婚夫一下，
So I grabbed my coat,
kissed my fiance on the cheek...
这是我们俩的最后一吻
for the last time in our lives
we would ever kiss...
然后我跑了
and I ran.
我到了警察局后，听他们说你殴打了一个大个儿的中国人
At the police station, they told me you had
beaten up a very large Chinese gentleman.
不是中国人，亲爱的，是个朝鲜人
至少我认为他是个朝鲜人
Not Chinese, dear, Korean.
At least, I think he was Korean.
一个大个儿的朝鲜人，但他们也向Washington将军确认了...
A large Korean gentleman, but that
you were a pretty solid type yourself...
你是个很可靠的人
according to Washington,
with whom they had checked.
所以我想...
So I figured...
如果他们敢麻烦Washington将军，要对你的评价...
if they'd bother to get a comment
on you from George Washington...
那你一定是个很重要的人物
you must be somebody
very important indeed.
我得说，这可不是警局通常的处理方式，
并且你只是个少校
I must say, it was rather sweet of
the general, with you only a major.
我还不知道你和Washington将军有联系
I didn't even know you knew him.
如果他们还对你有些小猜疑的话，他们应该问我
If they were the tiniest bit puzzled
about you, they could have asked me.
是的，确实，我亲爱的Ben...
Yes, indeed, my darling Ben...
他们应该问我...
they could have asked me...
我就会告诉他们...
and I would have told them...
- 好久不见，孩子
- 到底出什么事了？
- Hi, kid.
- What in the hell's going on?
我在华盛顿办事儿，他们打来电话说
你闯进了我的公寓...
They called me in Washington to tell me
you'd broken into my apartment...
殴打了我的男仆
and beaten up my houseboy.
是的，不过，你知道，春锦，当我...
Yeah, well, see, Chunjin, when I...
天啊，你气色怎么这么差？
我从来没见过你这么糟糕的样子
My God, you look terrible.
I've never seen you look so awful.
Raymond...
我是来告诉你我那可怕的噩梦的
I want to tell you that I've been
having this terrible nightmare.
我在军队服役十九年了
I've been in the army 19 years.
还是第一次见到勋章
First time I've ever seen
one of these.
我一直在做噩梦...
I've been having this nightmare...
不断重复的噩梦
a real swinger
of a nightmare, too.
梦里有各种各样的奇怪的人
It has to do with
all kinds of strange people.
有个苏联将军，一些中国人...
Is it about a Russian general
and some Chinese...
还有我和其他侦察队的成员？
and me and the men
who were on the patrol?
你怎么知道？
How did you know that?
把手拿开
Take your hands off me.
求你了，Raymond，告诉我，
你怎么知道的？
Please, Raymond, tell me,
how did you know?
我不是真的知道这个噩梦
I don't really know
anything about it.
- 但你刚刚告诉我...
- 你记得Al Melvin吗？
- But you just started to tell me...
- Do you remember Al Melvin?
- 侦察队里的下士？
- 是的，我知道
- The corporal in the patrol?
- Yes, of course.
我几个星期前收到了他的一封信
I had a letter from him
a couple of weeks ago.
不用说，收到他的来信我很惊讶
Needless to say, I was very surprised to hear from him.
你知道侦察队里的人有多恨我
You know how much
the guys in the outfit hated me.
当然，远不及我恨他们
Well, not as much as I hated them,
of course.
但是呢，有趣的一点是...
But anyway, the funny thing was...
他在信里说我是他在服役时最好的朋友
he said in his letter that I was
the best friend he had in the army.
我是他在服役时最好的朋友
I was the best friend
he had in the army.
这个可怜的，天真的傻蛋
The poor, simple boob.
然后，他想跟我说说他的噩梦
Anyway, he wanted to tell me
about his nightmare.
他说他快被折磨疯了
He said he was going out
of his mind.
告诉我，关于噩梦他都说了什么
Tell me what he said
about the nightmare.
他不断梦到整个侦察队坐在酒店礼堂里...
He keeps dreaming that the patrol
is sitting in a hotel lobby...
还有很多中国高级军官和苏联将军
and there are a lot of Chinese brass
and Russian generals...
然而这有什么可怕的？
Anyway, what's nightmarish
about that?
信呢？你还留着吗？
The letter?
Have you got the letter?
没有，我从不留信
No, I don't.
I never keep letters.
这就是他说的？再没了？
That's all he wrote?
That was the end of it?
怎么了？你梦到的是一样的东西吗？
Why? Is it the same thing
you've been dreaming?
能帮我个忙吗？
Do something for me, will you?
给黄金国59970打电话
Call Eldorado 59970.
如果是一个年轻的女士接的...
If a young lady answers...
告诉她我去了华盛顿，是地名，不是那个将军
tell her I've gone to Washington.
The town, not the general.
我会尽快和她联系的
I'll be in touch with her
as quickly as I can
你会帮我的吧？电话是黄金国59970
You'll do that, won't you?
Eldorado 59970.
为了解开这个谜团，我们会给你展示一些照片...
To take some of the mystery out of it,
the photographs you're looking at...
有男模，墨西哥马戏演员
are shots of male models,
Mexican circus performers...
捷克化学家
Czech research chemists...
日本罪犯
Japanese criminals...
法国领班
French headwaiters...
土耳其摔跤手，乡村精神科医生
Turkish wrestlers,
pastoral psychiatrists...
当然，还有很多苏联的...
and, of course, various
officials of the USSR...
中华人民共和国的...
the People's Republic of China...
苏联军队的官员
and the Soviet Army.
请把右边这张留下
Hold the one on the right, please.
这张也留下
Hold this one, too.
就在一小时前，你的朋友Alan Melvin先生...
Exactly one hour ago, your friend
Mr. Alan Melvin, in Alaska...
在阿拉斯加，也选了同样的照片
made the same two photographs.
他在梦里是戴着眼镜的，笑起来像个色魔
This one here wore sunglasses,
smelled like a goat.
胡子要稀一些，他的声音很洪亮，很刺耳
His moustache was a little thinner then.
He had a loud voice, and it grated.
他大约5尺11英寸高，偏胖
He's about 5-11,
on the heavy side.
穿着中将服
Uniformed as a lieutenant general.
他手下穿着平常衣服，
看起来像是一帮F.B.I的人
His staff wore civilian clothes.
They looked a little like F.B.I. Men.
顺便一提，他的名字是Berezovo
His name, incidentally, is Berezovo.
是中央委员会的成员
He's a member of
the Central Committee.
这个在梦里穿着便服，但手下都穿制服...
This one wore civilian clothes,
but his staff was uniformed...
上至上校下至中尉
varying from a full colonel
to a first lieutenant.
他们都是重要的政治人物
开灯
They wore political markings.
Lights.
开灯
我会向上面建议展开联合调查，联合中情局和联调局，
I'm going to recommend setting up
a joint-intelligence, C.I.A. F.B.I. Unit...
以纽约为大本营
based out of New York.
你会代表军队跟他们一起工作
You'll work with them,
representing the army.
- 你的助手是Raymond Shaw
- 很好，上校
- Your assignment's Raymond Shaw.
- Very good, Colonel.
他会是个好助手的，少校...
It should be a very pleasant
assignment, Major...
毕竟他是你遇到过的最友好，最勇敢...
considering that Raymond Shaw
is the kindest, bravest...
最热心，最完美的人
warmest, most wonderful human being
you've ever met in your life.
我的母亲，Ben，是个可怕的女人
My mother, Ben, is a terrible woman.
好可怕，好可怕的女人
A terrible, terrible woman.
春锦
Chunjin.
再来点儿红酒
We would like some more wine.
春锦
Chunjin.
哦，我忘了
Oh, I forgot.
在你给我打电话之后，我给了春锦一晚上的假
After you called,
I gave Chunjin the night off.
我告诉他，因为今天是圣诞前夜
Because it was Christmas Eve,
I told him.
他很不情愿地走了
He was very reluctant to go.
可能他是个佛教徒，不过圣诞节
That's probably because he's a Buddhist,
and he doesn't celebrate Christmas.
我不觉得春锦是个佛教徒
I don't think that Chunjin
is a Buddhist.
他总是微笑着，
He smiles all the time.
真遗憾
What a shame.
我觉得他信佛
I thought he was a Buddhist.
信的话我就会给他寄张圣诞贺卡了
Otherwise I would have sent him
a Christmas card.
但我想...
But I figured...
如果我在圣诞节给他寄贺卡...
that if I sent him a card
at this time of the year...
那他之后会在佛祖的生日给我寄贺卡的
then he would have to send me a card
on the Buddha's birthday.
- 要面子，对吧？
- 是啊
- To save face, right?
- Right.
这样的话整个事儿就会越来越复杂
And that would have started
a whole big magilla.
是的，你做得非常对
Exactly. You did exactly the right thing.
“圣诞节十二天”（注：BGM）
Twelve Days of Christmas.
圣诞节有一天就够烦人的了
One day of Christmas is loathsome enough.
我们刚刚聊什么来着？
对，我妈
What were we saying?
Oh, yes, my mother.
但你不会想听我说这个的...
But you don't want to listen to me
talking about...
不，说吧，我很感兴趣
Of course I do.
I'm interested.
这就和听俄瑞斯忒斯抱怨克吕泰墨斯特拉差不多
It's rather like listening to Orestes
gripe about Clytemnestra.
- 谁？
- 戏剧里的两个希腊人物
- Who?
- A couple of Greeks in a play.
你知道吗，Ben...
You know, Ben...
恨自己的母亲是件很可怕很糟糕的事
it's a terrible thing
to hate your mother.
但我不是一直都恨她
But I didn't always hate her.
当我还是个孩子时，我只是有点不喜欢她
When I was a child,
I only kind of disliked her.
但当她对我和Jocie做了那事之后...
But after what she did to
Jocie and me...
我就开始恨她了
that's when I began to hate her.
Jocie？
Jocie?
Jocie Jordan
Jocie Jordan.
Jordan参议员的女儿
Sen. Jordan's daughter.
这有点意思，不是吗？
That's pretty funny, isn't it?
Thomas Jordan的女儿
Thomas Jordan's daughter...
和Johnny Iselin的继子
and Johnny Iselin's stepson.
这就是她
That's her.
Jocie
Jocie.
- 她很可爱
- 我一直留着她的照片
- She's lovely.
- I always keep her picture.
几年后我认识到，Ben，
Years later, I realized,
Ben, that...
我不是个讨人喜欢的人
不，别反驳我
I'm not very lovable.
No, don't contradict me.
我不讨人喜欢
I am not lovable.
有些人很讨人喜欢但有些人不是
Some people are lovable,
and other people are not lovable.
我不是个讨人喜欢的人
I am not lovable.
但我跟Jocie在一起时，我就变成了讨人喜欢的人
But I was very lovable
with Jocie.
你不会相信我能变得多讨人喜欢
You can not believe
how lovable I was.
在某种程度上
In a way.
但是，我母亲把这一切都改变了
Then, of course,
my mother fixed all that.
Ben，你不会因为我恨自己的母亲
而责怪我吧？
Ben, you don't blame me
for hating my mother, do you?
我不是在找借口...
I'm not making excuses...
但在那事儿发生后...
but I have been even less lovable...
我确实变得比原来更不讨人喜欢了
than I was since.
那是我入伍前的最后一个夏天
It was the summer just before
I went into the army...
我被蛇咬了
and I was bitten by this snake.
- 你在听吗？
- 听着呢
- Are you following me?
- I am.
我当时无助地躺在地上，完全无助
While I was lying there,
absolutely helpless...
还不敢动，因为被蛇咬了，
我不能动...
afraid to move, because
you're not supposed to move...
一动就会加快毒素扩散
it makes the poison circulate...
然而，没想到，
when, unexpectedly,
there she was...
她拿出了剃刀刀片
with a razor blade in her hand.
我爸会很开心的
My daddy's going to be
so pleased about this.
我是说，他很害怕乡下的毒蛇
I mean, he's absolutely scared about
snakes in this part of the country.
我知道这听起来很弗洛伊德，但在我爸这个案例上，
我不觉得它是弗洛伊德型的案例
I know that sounds terribly Freudian,
but in this case, I don't think it is.
我觉得他只是单纯地害怕蛇，并且还是周期性的
I think he's just simply and uncomplicatedly
afraid of snakes, period...
这就是为什么我骑车还碰巧带着剃刀刀片...
which is why I happen to be
riding around with a razorblade...
和高锰酸钾溶液的原因
and a bottle of potassium
permanganate solution.
你不会碰巧也带着块儿手帕吧？
You don't happen to have
a handkerchief, do you?
不，当然了，你不会带
No, of course, you don't.
我也没带，我带着面巾纸，不过...
I don't either.
I do have a Kleenex.
讲真，我爸看见这场面会吓坏的
Seriously, Daddy is going to be
just thrilled about this.
整个夏天他都在胡说有蛇，
All summer long,
he's been raving about snakes...
没看到过那怕一条，但现在有了
and nobody's even seen one,
and now this.
我向你保证，被蛇咬可能让你觉得不爽，
I promise you,
it may be uncomfortable for you...
但这让我爸的夏天圆满了
but it's going to absolutely
make his summer.
现在你慢慢躺下，千万别动
Now you just lie very still.
Don't move.
这很重要
That's very important.
我很快开车回来接你
I'll be right back with the car
in a minute.
你很幸运，年轻人，非常幸运
You're lucky,
young man, very lucky.
如果我告诉你每年有多少人被蛇咬致死...
If I were to tell you the statistics
on death by snake bite every year...
但看你身上，我觉得...
上面和下面都没有肿
But in this case, I think...
There's no swelling above or below.
体温正常
Normal.
我得说，你会活下来的
I must say, there's a good chance
you're going to live.
你不会是个哑巴吧？
You are not, by any chance,
a mute, are you?
我得好好地感谢你，你叫...
I want to thank you
very much, Miss...
- Jordan
- Jocelyn Jordan小姐
- Jordan.
- Miss Jocelyn Jordan.
- 你好
- How do you do?
- Hi.
现在，根据本地习俗...
And now, according to
the quaint local custom...
- 该你告诉我们你叫什么了
- 先生，我叫Raymond Shaw
- it's your turn to tell us what your name is.
- My name is Raymond Shaw, sir.
你好，Raymond
How do you do, Raymond?
你的住处在这附近吗？
Is your place near here?
是的，湖对面那栋红房子就是
Yes, it's that red house
just across the lake.
- Iselin家的房子？
- 是我的房子
- The Iselin house?
- My house.
那是我爸的，我爸死了，他把房子留给了我
It was my father's.
My father's dead, he left it to me.
我们听说那是Iselin参议员的夏季别墅
We were told that that was
the summer camp of Sen. Iselin.
先生，Johnny有时会过来呆一会儿...
Johnny stays there sometimes, sir.
当他喝得烂醉时，我妈不允许他在华盛顿被别人看见喝的烂醉
When he gets too drunk for my mother
to allow him to be seen in Washington.
亲爱的，我们已经做了所有现代科学建议我们做的...
My dear, although we've done everything
that modern science recommends...
但还是有一些传统的民间的治蛇咬伤的方法，我们还没试
there's still the traditional folk remedy
against snake bite, which we haven't applied.
因此，为了安全起见...
So, to be on the safe side...
- Iselin太太是你的母亲？
- 是的，先生
- Mrs. Iselin is your mother?
- Yes, sir.
我曾觉得有必要起诉你的母亲，
并且起诉了她...
I once found it necessary
to sue your mother...
因为她诽谤中伤我的人格
for defamation of character
and slander.
我是Thomas Jordan
参议员Thomas Jordan
My name is Thomas Jordan.
Sen. Thomas Jordan.
那个共产党员？
The Communist?
你妈妈有一个很可爱的特点...
One of your mother's
more endearing traits...
她喜欢把和她政见不同的人称为...
is hertendency to referto anyone
who disagrees with her about anything...
共产党员
as a Communist.
上一次她在一个广播节目中这么叫我...
The last time she so referred to me
on a network radio program...
让她交了六万五千块罚款还有诉讼费
it cost her $ 65,000
and court costs.
比起罚款，我觉得...
What hurt her more
than the money, I think...
我把这笔钱捐给了美国民权同盟...
was the fact that I donated it...
这个做法伤她更深
to an organization called
the American Civil Liberties Union.
- Jordan参议员？
- 说吧，Raymond
- Sen. Jordan?
- Yes, Raymond.
我请求你允许我娶你的女儿
I would very much like to ask
your permission to marry Jocelyn.
之后我们每一分钟都在一起
We were together every
minute after that.
你不会相信的，Ben...
You just can not believe, Ben...
你不会相信这整件事有多甜蜜
how lovable the whole
damn thing was.
整个夏天我们都在一起，
All summer long, we were together.
我那时很可爱...
I was lovable...
Jocie很可爱...
Jocie was lovable...
参议员很可爱...
the Senator was lovable...
白天很可爱,晚上也很可爱...
the days were lovable,
the nights were lovable...
每个人都很可爱...
and everybody was lovable.
除了，当然...
Except, of course...
我的母亲
my mother.
什么事，妈？
What is it, Mother?
你凌晨三点半出去见谁了？
What sort of a greeting
is that at 3:30 a.m?
- 是两点四十五，你想干嘛？
- 我想跟你谈谈，Raymond
- It's 2:45 and what do you want?
- I want to talk to you, Raymond.
谈什么？
About what?
- 谈谈那个共产党婊子
- 闭嘴吧，妈，闭嘴！
- About that Communist tart.
- Shut up，mother，shut up！
你知道Jordan是什么人吗？
你是想公开羞辱我吗？
Do you know what Jordan is?
Are you out to crucify me?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know
what you're talking about.
我要睡觉了
I'm going to bed.
Raymond，坐下
Raymond, sit down.
你以后怎么见她？他们住在纽约
How would you see her?
They live in New York.
我会去纽约找份工作
I'm getting a job in New York.
- 你要去服兵役
- 服兵役
- You have your army service.
- Next spring.
我可能没服完兵役就死了
I might be dead by next spring.
Raymond，如果我们和苏联开战了...
Raymond, if we were at war...
而你却迷上了一个苏联特务的女儿...
and you suddenly became infatuated
with the daughter of a Russian agent...
你难道不会希望我来找你，反对你，
wouldn't you expect me
to come to you and object...
求你在一切太迟之前停下你那疯狂的爱吗？
and beg you to stop the entire thing
before it was too late?
然而，我们已经开战了
Well, we are at war.
是冷战
It's a cold war...
但会越来越严重的，直到这个国家的每个男人，
每个女人，每个儿童，
but it will get worse, until every
man, woman and child in this country...
都不得不站起来，表明自己...
will have to stand up
and be counted...
是站在权利和自由这边，
to say whether they are
on the side of right and freedom...
还是站在Thomas Jordan的国家那边
or on the side of
the Thomas Jordans of this country.
我明天就和你一起去华盛顿...
I will go with you to Washington,
tomorrow, if you like...
如果你想，我会给你看证据，
证明这个男人是站在邪恶那边的
and I will show you proof
that this man stands for evil.
证明他是个邪恶的人
That he is evil.
他穷尽一生，在暗中损害你和我的，
And that his whole life is devoted to
undermining everything that you and I...
Johnny的，每个有自由思想的美国人的
生活中的所有东西
and Johnny
and every freedom-minded American...
她赢了，当然
She won, of course.
她总是赢的那一个
She always does.
我永远没法打败她
I could never beat her.
现在也做不到
I still can't.
我写了封信...
I wrote a letter...
或者是她写的，我签的名，
我记不清了
or she wrote it and I signed it,
I can't even remember which.
那是封可怕的，卑鄙的，恶心的信
It was a terrible, vile,
disgusting letter.
第二天我就入伍了
The next day,
I enlisted in the army.
我再也没见过她
I never saw her again.
有些事只有上帝知道，Ben...
God knows, Ben...
我不讨人喜欢
I'm not lovable.
但我爱她
But I loved her.
我爱她，我现在仍然爱着她
I did love her.
I do love her.
行了，孩子，我送你上床吧
Come on, kid.
Time for you to call it a night.
所以我对我那个讨厌的姐夫说...
So this lousy brother-in-law of mine,
I say to him...
- “你觉得你扑克玩的好？但我记得...
- 来杯啤酒
- ‘You think you're a poker player?
Well, I got a flash for you.
- Beer
你玩的不好啊"
（注：此处扑克有赌博性质）
You ain't no poker player.'
于是我对他说
So I says to him
“我给你个发自内心的忠告...
'My advice to you,
from the bottom of the heart...
别玩扑克
don't play poker.
如果我是你，我会玩点别的类型的
If I was you, I'd get myself
another line of action.
为什么不玩玩单人纸牌打发时间呢？”
Why don't you pass the time
by playing a little solitaire? '
- 然后他说...
- 请给我一副牌
- So he says...
- Give me a deck of cards, please.
当我和我老婆结婚时，我不明白...
When I got married to my old lady,
I got no idea that this guy...
为什么这个人也跟着住进我家，
原来这是个一揽子买卖
comes in the same package,
that it's a package deal.
11年了，这个问题一直困扰着我
For 11 long years,
I got this crumb tied around my neck.
- 相信我，这交易可不便宜
- 请来杯啤酒
- Believe me, it's no bargain.
- A beer, please.
抱歉我迟到了孩子
路上很堵
Sorry I'm late, kid.
Got held up in traffic.
于是我对他说：“你能帮我个忙吗？
So I says to him,
'Do me a favor, will you?
你为什么不出去打辆车，去中央公园...
Why don't you go and take yourself
a cab and go up to Central Park...
然后跳湖里呢？”
and go jump in the lake? '
快上来
Get out of there.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
你好，Ben
Hi, Ben.
你在干嘛？你疯了吗？
What the hell are you doing?
What's the matter with you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我刚才和你一起在酒吧里，
你在玩单人纸牌，你记得吗？
I was next to you at the bar,
you were playing solitaire. Do you remember that？
然后你突然冲出酒吧，打了辆车来公园...
Then you bolted out of the bar,
took a cab to the park...
然后跳进了湖里
and jumped into the water.
我什么都不记得了，Ben
I don't remember, Ben.
我就是想不起来发生了什么
I just don't remember.
等一下，我想起来点什么
Wait a minute, I do.
I remember.
梦里的一些事
In the dream.
我想起来你在梦里干了些什么了
I remember what you were doing
with your hands.
你在...原来是这样！
You were... Of course.
很明显，单人纸牌游戏是某种东西的触发机制
Obviously, the solitaire game serves
as some kind of trigger mechanism.
把黑7放红8上
Black 7 on the red 8.
我建议放弃数字牌，集中精力研究花牌
I suggest we discard the various number
systems and concentrate on the face cards.
- 红6放黑7上
- 非常感谢
- Red 6 on the black 7.
- Thanks a lot.
因为花牌象征着人类
Because of their symbolic
identification with human beings.
基于对Raymond的精神病模式分析，我们可以
安全地排除杰克和国王
Based on Raymond's psychiatric pattern,
we can safely eliminate jacks and kings.
黑6放红7上
Black 6 on the red 7.
还是你玩吧
Why don't you try it for a while?
人鱼在大气海洋的底部游泳，
Human fish swimming at the bottom
of the ocean of atmosphere...
当他们和另外的人鱼相撞，就会产生精神伤害
develop psychic injuries
as they collide with one another.
大多数凡人...
Most mortal of all...
是继承了上一辈的残留的那些人
are those gotten
from the parent fish.
方块女王放在黑国王上
Queen of Diamonds on the black king.
嘿，你在干嘛？
Hey, what are you doing?
- 在单人纸牌游戏里作弊是退化的一种方式
- 我想起来了
- To cheat at solitaire is a form of regression.
- I remember.
我想起来了
I remember.
我能看见一个中国人在那儿站着，
笑起来像傅满洲
I can see that Chinese cat
standing there smiling like Fu Manchu...
还说：“方片女王可以通过多种方式...
and saying, 'The Queen of Diamonds
is reminiscent in many ways...
让Raymond想起他那让他又爱又恨的母亲...
of Raymond's dearly loved
and hated mother... '
这是触发让他进行任何种类任务的机制...
and is the second key
to clear the mechanism... '
的第二把钥匙”
for any other assignment.'
...我们伟大的共和国，我重复一遍，共和国...
'... our great republic, repeat, republic... '
直到把国际共产主义的危险...
'until the peril
of international Communism... '
从这个伟大的国家里驱逐出去，
甚至从这个国家每一个黑暗的角落里驱逐出去
'is driven from every dark corner
of this great nation.'
再给我弄弄下巴
Give me a little chucky
under the chin.
我好担心Raymond
I can't tell you how worried
I am， about Raymond.
- Raymond？谁啊？
- Raymond Shaw，我儿子，你的继子
- Raymond? What Raymond?
- Raymond Shaw. My son. Your stepson.
我一直在想他，你知道我决定要干嘛吗？
I've been thinking about him,
and you know what I've decided?
- 你要干嘛？
- 我觉得是时候让他结婚了
- What?
- I've decided it's time he got married.
我能问你什么事这么好笑吗？
May I ask what you find
so amusing?
你能找谁？谁会嫁给Raymond啊？
Who could you possibly find，
who would marry Raymond?
我已经仔细考虑过这个问题了
I have devoted considerable thought
to the problem.
我想到了Tom Jordan的女儿，Jocelyn
It has occurred to me
that Tom Jordan's daughter Jocelyn...
你记得吗亲爱的...
you remember her, hon...
那年夏天，在湖边，把Raymond迷的不要不要的
那个跟老鼠似的女孩？
that mousy little girl Raymond was so
attracted to that summer at the lake?
- 那个小共产党婊子？
- 对！
- That little 'Communist tart'?
- All right!
- 我当时可能有点草率了
- 发际线这边再刮一下
- I may have been hasty.
- A little in the hair line.
然而，时代变了，我现在认为她会成为
Raymond的好妻子
Anyway, times change. I now think
she would make Raymond an excellent wife.
她过去两年都住在巴黎
She's been living in Paris
for the past two years.
我听说她快要回来了
I have word she'll be
coming home soon.
等她回来了，我想我们应该开个小聚会
When she does, I think we should
give a little party.
但是，宝贝儿，我觉得你和Jordan参议员...
But, babe, I thought
that you and Sen. Jordan...
我告诉过你不要思考
I keep telling you not to think.
你在很多方面都很行...
You're very, very good
at a great many things...
但是思考，亲爱的，不是你擅长的事
but thinking, hon,
just simply isn't one of them.
你只要对着电视镜头不断地喊“注意议事程序”就行了
You just keep shouting, 'Point of order,'
into the television cameras...
其他的事我会处理
and I'll handle the rest.
- 我觉得在六月办婚礼不错
- 威士忌，加水
- I think a June wedding would be nice.
- Bourbon, water.
正好在大选之前
Right before the convention.
我不明白为什么你的公寓...
I don't know why yours is
the only apartment in New York City...
是全纽约唯一一间没有空调的公寓
without an air conditioner.
有时候我觉得你是从另一个世纪来的
Sometimes I think you came to us
from another century.
春秋瞅？不管你名字怎么念了...
Chu-chin-chow,
or whatever your name is...
牛排必须两面各烤11分钟...
the steaks are to be broiled
for exactly 11 minutes...
不能多也不能少，还要放在400度预热的烤架上
no more, no less, on each side
in a preheated grill at 400 degrees.
好的，太太
Yes, ma'am.
妈，我能问个问题吗？
Mother, may I ask a question?
当然
Of course.
你在这儿干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我是说，为什么我们现在要进行“年会”？
一年见你一次我也不愿意
I mean，why are we having our annual meeting?
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what
you're talking about.
当我收到你要来吃午饭的消息时，
When I got your message,
announcing you were coming for lunch...
我自然地想到，你是想来干点什么
I naturally assumed
you wanted something.
当然不是，这只是个纯粹的社交活动，然而...
Not at all. This is a purely
social event. However...
哈！“然而”这个词好
Ha！“However”.
不知道你听没听说，Johnny和我要举办一个盛大的派对
As you may or may not have heard,
Johnny and I are giving an enormous party.
实际上，是个化妆舞会，在我们在长岛的度夏别墅
A costume ball, actually,
at the summer house on Long Island.
我想知道你是否会出席
I wondered if you'd like to attend?
你没疯吧，我会去吗？
Have you gone out of your mind?
我问你是因为这个聚会是为了你的一位老朋友而办的...
The reason I ask is because we're giving it
in honor of an old friend of yours...
还有他的女儿
and her father.
哪个老朋友？
What old friend?
你还记得入伍前我们遇到过的那个可爱的女孩吗？
Do you remember a darling girl we met
before you went into the army?
Jocelyn Jordan，Jordan参议员的女儿？
Jocelyn Jordan,
Sen. Jordan's daughter?
她近几年都在国外侨居
She's been living abroad
for the last several years.
大约一个周之前回到了纽约
She arrived back in New York
a week or so ago.
然后我想...
And I thought...
考虑到你曾那么卑鄙地对待她...
considering the rather shabby way
you treated her...
如果我给她举行个欢迎派对会是个友好的信号
it might be a rather gracious gesture
if I gave her a coming-home party.
Jocie和她爸...
Jocie and her father...
要去你们举办的派对？
coming to a party of yours?
当然...
Of course...
只要我跟她说你也会去
once I explained to her
you would be there.
没事儿，这是波兰鱼子酱
It's all right,
it's Polish caviar.
Johnny，过来，亲爱的
Johnny, come over here, hon.
你站中间
You stand in the middle.
- 谢谢，过会儿见
- 你看起来真美
- Thank you. See you later.
- You look marvelous.
- 她在哪儿？来了吗？
- 他们马上到
- Where is she? Have they come?
- They'll be here any minute.
妈，你确定他们会来吗？
百分之百确定？
Are you sure they're coming, Mother?
Absolutely sure?
Raymond，别像个傻瓜一样
Raymond, don't be such a jerk.
去拿杯喝的，要不就吃片安定
Go and get yourself a drink
or a tranquilizer or something.
Raymond肯定会变成让别人引以为戒的惨痛教训的
Raymond can certainly be a royal pain.
她在开玩笑，你看起来很棒，很棒！
She's just kidding.
You look great. Just great!
你在扮什么？某个荷兰滑冰选手？
What are you supposed to be,
one of those Dutch skaters?
Raymond，亲爱的...
Raymond, darling...
为什么你总是看起来很严肃紧张呢？
Why must you always look as if
your head's about to come to a point?
耐心点，她会来的，我保证
Now just be patient, and she'll be here.
I guarantee it.
Raymond，咱们到处溜达一会儿...
Raymond, why don't we just sneak away
for a few minutes...
然后找个地方坐下来安静地喝杯酒怎么样？
and sit down somewhere quietly
and have a drink?
你百分之百确定她会来，是吧，妈？
Are you absolutely sure
she's coming, Mother?
我跟你说了，她几分钟前从旅馆给我打电话了，会来
I told you, she telephoned me
minutes ago from the hotel.
- 妈，她听起来怎么样？
- 听起来像个女孩儿
- Mother, how did she sound?
- Like a girl.
你玩会儿单人纸牌游戏打发打发时间好吗？
Why don't you pass the time
by playing a little solitaire?
Tom老弟，你能来真是太好了
Tom boy, so great you could come.
我会来这个法西斯集会...
I am here at this fascist rally...
只是因为我的女儿告诉我...
because my daughter has assured me...
这对她的幸福很重要，所以我来了
that it was important to her happiness
that I come.
再没有其他原因
There is no other reason.
好心的Tom老弟
Good old Tom.
时间到了，咱们得好好谈谈
The time has come for us to have
a serious discussion.
我们觉得...谁啊？
We feel... What is it?
是我，宝贝儿，Johnny，
Tom Jordan来了，我需要你
It's me, babe, Johnny.
Tom Jordan's here. I need you.
我过会儿就出去！
I'll be right out!
- 你和谁在里面啊？
- Raymond！
- Who's in there with you, anyway?
- Raymond!
快点儿好吗？外面还有工作呢
Hurry it up, will you?
We've got work to do out here.
- 我会拿着这张的，亲爱的，留在这儿会出事的
- 好的
- I'll take this one with me, dear.
It might be mischief if I leave it.
- Yes.
我很快就回来
I'll be back as soon as I can.
我一直在窗外看着你，
I've been watching you through the window.
当我看着你时，我的心都要跳出来了
When I saw you, my heart almost
shot out of my body.
我让爸爸去前门，
I sent Daddy around the front way.
我想一个人看着你
I had to see you alone.
走吧，亲爱的
Come on, lover.
- 你为什么不拿着这杯酒找个地方安安静静地喝呢？
- 但是，亲爱的...
- Why don't you just take that somewhere
very quietly and drink it?
- But，hon...
好啦，亲爱的，快去吧，
成年人要开始会谈了
All right, dear, run along.
The grownups have to talk.
你能来真好，Tom
How good of you to come, Tom.
我跟你丈夫解释过我来的原因了
I have explained to your husband
why I am here.
我知道你对我和Johnny有很大的偏见
I know you have strong personal
feelings about Johnny and I.
我想知道这种偏见到底有多大
What I would like to find out is
how strong they really are.
简单地说吧...
To put it as simply as possible...
如果下周的竞选中Johnny被提名了...
If Johnny's name were put forward
at the convention next week...
你会试图阻止他吗？
would you attempt to block him?
你一定是在开玩笑
You're joking, of course.
Stevenson先生会开玩笑，我不会
Mr. Stevenson makes jokes. I do not.
你真的在帮Johnny争取提名吗？
You're seriously trying
for the nomination for Johnny?
不，我们做不到
No. We couldn't make it.
但我觉得他有很大的机会获得第二提名，得到候补机会
But I think he has a good chance
for the second spot.
我回答了你的问题，你还没回答我的
I've answered your question,
but you haven't answered mine.
- 什么问题？
- 你会阻止我们吗？
- What question?
- Will you block us?
我会阻止你们吗？
Will I block you?
我会花掉我的每一分钱，然后再借我能借到的所有钱，
都用来阻止你们
I would spend every cent I own
and all I could borrow to block you.
有人认为Johnny是个小丑，是个弄臣
There are people who think of Johnny
as a clown and a buffoon.
但我不这么认为，
But I do not.
我鄙视John Iselin...
I despise John Iselin...
和所有他的政治主张中支持的东西
and everything that Iselinism
has come to stand for.
我觉得如果John Iselin是个苏联特务的话
I think if John Iselin
were a paid Soviet agent...
他所做的也不会比他现在所做的，伤害这个国家更深了
he could not do more to harm this country
than he is doing now.
你问了我一个问题...
You asked me a question...
好的，我这就回答你
very well,
I'll answer you.
如果你试图跟代表们走关系...
If you attempt to deal
with the delegates...
或者试图让Johnny获得提名...
or cause Johnny's name
to be brought forward on the ticket...
又或者明天早上我和代表们通话时，我发现你为竞选一直没闲着...
or if in my canvass of the delegates
I find that you are acting...
我会在美国参议院开会时...
I will bring impeachment proceedings
against your husband...
弹劾你的丈夫
on the floor of the United
States Senate.
我会把他打趴下的，我保证...
And I will hit him, I promise you...
用我那记得满满的档案薄
with everything in my
well-documented book.
抽张牌，赌一百万我能猜到是什么
For $ 1 million, pick a card.
- 纸牌把戏，要是我知道...
- 抽一张
- Card tricks. If I know that...
- Pick a card.
是方块皇后
The Queen of Diamonds.
不错啊，你怎么做到的？
That's pretty good.
How did you do that?
这就是奥秘，亲爱的，整副牌都是骗人的
This is what is known, my dear girl,
as a forced deck.
职业魔术师经常使用这种牌，
This deck of cards is often employed
by a professional magician...
让他的“叫第三排的小老太太抽张牌我猜”
把戏变得更简单
to simplify his problem of guessing the card
picked by the little old lady in the third row.
陆军情报工作者也会使用它...
Also employed by
Army Intelligence officers who...
Rosie，咱们结婚吧
Rosie, let's get married.
- 咱们今晚真是热情高涨不是吗？
- 是啊
- We certainly are in good spirits tonight，are we？
- Yes we are.
明天是个大日子
Tomorrow's the big day.
和Raymond一起吃午饭...
Lunch with Raymond...
然后一起玩玩单人纸牌游戏...
then a nice little game
of solitaire...
然后好好地聊聊那些在朝鲜度过的美好的往昔
and a nice long chat
about the good old days in Korea...
还有我们的一些中国和苏联的朋友
and some old Chinese
and Russian friends of ours.
然后给他点暗示，除掉身体里的一切操纵链接...
Then a suggestion ortwo
to rip out all of the wiring...
然后，亲爱的，一切就都结束了
and then, dear girl, it's over.
All over.
- 怎么回事儿，你不想吗？
- 不想干嘛？
- What's the matter, don't you want to?
- Want to what?
结婚啊，我跟你说话时你怎么不留心听？
Get married. Why don't you pay
attention to me when I speak to you?
Bennie，我想和你结婚的念头远超过
继续吃意大利菜的想法...
Bennie, I want to marry you more than
I want to go on eating Italian food...
这会让你有个清楚的概念
which will give you some idea.
那咱们开始干吧，宝贝儿？
Then why don't we get with it, kiddo?
像是，准备文件，准备血检，发请柬...
You know, arranging for the papers,
for the blood test, posting the banns...
想想给孩子取什么名，准备酒席...
figure out what we're gonna name the kids,
renting the rice...
- 买戒指，通知父母
- 父母？
- buy the ring, call the folks.
- Folks?
你也没有？孤儿？
You neither? Orphan?
我以前一直认为自己是
从火星飞来的太空船上的唯一幸存者
I used to be convinced that I was the sole
survivor of a spaceship that overshot Mars.
这个故事非常性感，非常非常性感
Very sexy stuff. Very, very sexy.
- Ben！
- 你好，Raymond
- Ben!
- Hello, Raymond.
Ben,我想让你见见Jocie
记得吗？我跟你讲过我和她的故事？
Ben, I want you to meet Jocie.
Remember, I told you about her?
这是我的朋友，Ben Marco少校
This is my friend, Maj. Ben Marco.
- Jordan小姐
- 你好，少校
- Miss Jordan.
- How do you do, Major?
只是，我已经不再是Jordan小姐了，
是Shaw太太，Raymond Shaw的妻子
Only, it's not Miss Jordan anymore.
It's Mrs. Shaw. Mrs. Raymond Shaw.
我们昨晚飞去了马里兰州，在那儿结了婚
刚回来
We flew to Maryland last night.
We got married. We Just got back.
你不打算开瓶香槟或是上街上跳舞...
Aren't you going to pop champagne,
or dance in the streets...
- 或者至少亲一下新娘》
- 恭喜你们
- or at least kiss the bride?
- Congratulations.
Ben，她好美
Ben, isn't she beautiful?
我是全世界最幸运的男人
Am I not the luckiest guy
in the whole world?
你不用回答，不管怎么说，我都是个幸运儿
You don't have to answer that.
Anyway, I'm the one who's lucky.
听着，亲爱的，这儿一定有啤酒或者香槟...
Listen, darling, there must be
some beer or champagne...
或者青霉素滴眼液，冰箱里或许还有点凤尾鱼
or penicillin eye-drops
or some anchovies in the ice box.
去看看都有什么吧，咱们三个得好好喝一杯
Crack open whatever it is.
The three of us have got to have a drink.
来吧，干起来，像个家庭主妇那样
Come on, bustle.
Make like a housewife.
我先脱下这套傻乎乎的衣服
I'll get out of this idiot suit.
Ben，你真应该看看法官的表情
Ben, you should've seen the judge's face.
我们俩在那儿，一个是方块皇后，我打扮的像谁...
我不知道...
There we were, the Queen of Diamonds
and me looking like, I don't know...
像Groucho Marx
like Groucho Marx.
Groucho Marx？
Groucho Marx?
Ben，我刚刚开了个玩笑
Ben, I just made a joke.
不是个好玩笑，我承认，但是个玩笑
Not a very good joke,
I admit, but a joke.
你之前听过我开玩笑嘛？
Have you ever before
heard me make a joke?
我刚刚开了一个玩笑，Groucho Marx，我
I just made one.
Groucho Marx，me.
今天是个好日子！你得把今天记下来
Big day! Mark that down in your book.
Raymond Shaw不但结婚了，还开了个玩笑
Raymond Shaw got married,
and he made a joke.
Groucho Marx
Groucho Marx.
“方块皇后”？这是什么意思？
'The Queen of Diamonds? '
What did he mean，The Queen of Diamonds?
是我的装扮，我扮成方块皇后去的派对
My costume. I came to this costume party
as the Queen of Diamonds.
我不知道穿什么好，然后我在商店看到了
一套大扑克牌服装
I didn't know what to wear.
Then I saw this big playing card in a shop.
Shaw太太
少校，请叫我Jocie
Mrs. Shaw.
Please, Major, Jocie.
少校，请叫我Jocie
你叫我Jocie，我叫你Ben
You call me Jocie,
I'll call you Ben.
Shaw太太，Jocie...
Mrs. Shaw, Jocie...
我今天早上来是要...
the reason I came here
this morning...
问问Raymond愿不愿意自愿被捕
is to ask Raymond to voluntarily
put himself under arrest.
什么？
What?
不像是逮捕，这个词重了，但是...
Maybe not under arrest,
that's pretty strong, but...
是让他自愿接受审问
to surrender himself
for some questioning.
审问？什么样的审问？
Questioning?
What kind of questioning?
Raymond病了，Shaw太太，一种特别的病
Raymond is sick, Mrs. Shaw,
in a kind of a special way.
- 他自己还没有意识到
- 病了？他可没病
- He doesn't even realize it himself.
- Sick? He's not sick.
他是我见过的最健康的人
He's the healthiest man I've seen
in my whole life.
- 你看看他就知道了
- 我不是说身体上的病
- You can tell that by just looking at him.
- That's not the kind of sick I mean.
你错了，Ben, 你错了
You're wrong, Ben. You're wrong.
他的内心很混乱，就像有几千个结一样
我知道
He's tied up inside, in a thousand knots,
I know that.
但你应该看看他和我在一起时的样子
But you can see for yourself
how he is with me.
我们六个小时前刚结婚
We were married just six hours ago.
我们在车里，在办公室里，在飞机上
每一分每一秒都在一起
We've been in cars and offices
and airplanes ever since.
你们有什么计划？
What are your plans?
有家小旅馆，叫贝福德之家，
在离贝福德村很近的地方
There's an inn, The Bedford House,
near Bedford village...
离这儿大约一小时的路程
it's about an hour from here.
现在是淡季，几乎没什么人
There's hardly anyone there
this early in the season.
我们已经订好了房间
We've already wired for a room.
Ben，你得相信我，我会让他恢复健康的
Ben, you've got to believe me and trust me,
I can make him well.
我给你48小时，后天带他回来
I'll give you 48 hours. Have him
back here day after tomorrow.
我到时再和他谈
I'll talk to him then.
之后的事，再看吧
After that, we'll see.
谢谢你，Ben
Thank you, Ben.
谢谢你，上帝会保佑你的
Thank you, and God bless you.
亲爱的
Darling.
什么事？
What?
没事
Nothing.
只想叫你一声亲爱的
Just darling.
我亲爱的姑娘...
My dear girl...
你注意到人类被分为两种截然不同又无法调和的群体了吗？
have you noticed the human race is divided
into two distinct and irreconcilable groups?
一群人走进房间，不自觉地把电视打开...
Those who walk into rooms
and automatically turn television sets on...
另一群人走进来，又不自觉地把电视关上
and those who walk into rooms
and automatically turn them off.
问题是，两群人还经常通婚，这自然就导致了...
The problem is they usually
marry each other, which naturally causes a great deal...
Jocelyn Jordan，Thomas Jordan参议员的女儿...
... elopement of Jocelyn Jordan,
daughter of Sen. Thomas Jordan...
和朝鲜战争英雄，Raymond Shaw，
John Iselin的继子，两人已经私奔...
and Korean war hero, Raymond Shaw,
stepson of Sen. John Iselin.
看起来...
- 我的罗密欧
- It appears that this...
- My Romeo.
这种罗密欧与朱丽叶式的结合，
没有对两党领导人...
... the Montague-Capulet note
would have little effect on the feud
之间的不和产生多大影响
now raging between
the two party leaders.
今早，Iselin参议员在他的竞选大本营...
From his campaign headquarters,this morning
Senator Iselin stepped up his charges
向这位反对他获得提名的政党领导人提出了控诉
against the leader of the group,
attempting to block his nomination.
我现在控告这个男人，Thomas Jordan，
I now charge this man, Thomas Jordan,
犯了严重的叛国罪
with high treason
并且我保证，当参议院再开会的时候...
And I assure you,
the moment the Senate reconvenes...
我会弹劾Jordan！
I shall move for
this man Jordan's impeachment!
之后，再对他进行全民审判
and after that，a civil trial.
快去穿好衣服，回纽约去
Come on, get dressed.
We're driving down to New York.
直接去你爸家
Go straight to your father's house.
替我向他道个歉，我之后再和你会合
Convey my personal apologies to him.
I'll join you later.
你要干嘛？
What are you going to do?
做点我早就应该做的事
Something I should have done
a long time ago.
我要去打死那个卑鄙无耻乱造谣的混蛋！
I'm going to beat that vile, slandering,
son-of-a-numbskull to a bloody pulp!
妈！
Mother!
你那个卑鄙乱造谣的丈夫在哪儿？
That vile, slandering husband of yours,
where is he?
亲爱的，出了很重要的事，你必须得做点什么
Darling，something very important has come up.
There is something you have to do.
谁啊？
Who is it?
是我，先生
It's me, sir.
Raymond，我的孩子
Raymond, my boy.
Jocie等了你好久，她一小时前就睡了
Jocie waited up as long as she could.
She turned in about one hour.
她把好消息告诉我了
She told me the good news.
我恭喜你们并且欢迎你加入我们家
I want to offer my congratulations
and welcome you to the family.
我整整一晚都在看我女儿的脸
I've been watching my daughter's face
all evening.
- 她很快乐
- 谢谢你，先生
- She's a very happy girl.
- Thank you, sir.
跟我来，我给你倒点好酒...
Come with me.
I'll force some good whiskey on you...
你们结婚了，得庆祝一下，
忙了一天你也得喝一杯平静平静
to celebrate your wedding,
soothe you after a trying day，any number of reasons.
你身旁的橱柜里有威士忌，自己倒吧
There's some whiskey in that cabinet
beside you. Help yourself.
我只希望Iselin那些愚蠢的抨击不会让你太烦心
I only hope you haven't been too much
upset by these idiotic attacks of Iselin's.
实际上我早就把他的抨击都当成荣耀了
Actually, I take the position
that any attack by Iselin is a great honor.
并且在过去的22年里我从未有过这么多的支持者
Actually, I haven't had so much supporting
mail in the Senate in the last 22 years.
我很高兴听到这个，先生
I'm very glad to hear that, sir.
你手里拿着什么？
What the hell is that in your hand?
是把手枪，先生
It's a pistol, sir.
还是把消音的？
Is that a silencer?
你带把手枪干嘛？
Why are you carrying a pistol?
Raymond...
爸，是谁来了？
Daddy, what is it?
Ben，出什么事了？
Ben, what is it?
Raymond Shaw今早射杀了他的妻子
Raymond Shaw shot and killed his wife
early this morning.
- 上面没说是他干的...
- 我知道
- But it doesn't say...
- I know.
并不真的是Raymond干的
It wasn't Raymond that really did it.
从某种程度上说，是我干的
In a way, it was me.
你们都知道，先生们...
As you can well understand,
gentlemen...
我妻子对失去这样一位可爱完美的女孩感到十分痛心...
my wife is prostrate over the loss
of this dear and wonderful girl...
她就像爱自己的女儿一样爱她
whom she loved as a daughter.
参议员先生，你的继子现在在哪儿？
And your stepson, Senator,
where is he?
我的儿子Raymond把自己藏了起来...
My son Raymond's in retreat...
向上帝祈求力量与理解...
praying for strength
and understanding...
尝试让自己从悲伤中走出来，继续生活
to try and carry on somehow.
Ben，找你的
Ben, it's for you.
我是Marco少校
Maj. Marco speaking.
为什么会有人...Jocie
How could anyone... Jocie.
怎么会出这种事？
How could it happen?
你在哪儿，Raymond？
Where are you, Raymond?
我觉得我要疯了
I think maybe I'm going crazy.
我开始做恶梦了...那些噩梦就像，
你以前做过的那些一样...
I'm having... terrible dreams
like you used to have and...
你在哪儿？咱们最好当面谈
告诉我你在哪儿
Where are you? We can't talk on
the telephone. Just tell me where you are.
我在一家宾馆的房间里
I'm in a hotel room...
在花园对面
across from the Garden.
在第八大街
Eighth Avenue side
4号房
Room 4.
好的，听好，在那里等我，我十分钟内肯定到
All right. Listen to me. Wait there.
I'll be there in 10 minutes.
别乱走动，就在那儿等我
Don't move, just wait right there.
好的，我现在去见见他
Okay, I'll take him now.
注意，万事都要小心处置
Everything's got to move quite normally.
我会让他觉得自己很安全，给我一副牌
I want him to feel like he's safe.
Just give me a pack of cards.
他们刚刚把副总统提名给了那个白痴Iselin
They just handed the vice-presidential
nomination to that idiot Iselin.
你好，孩子
Hi, kid.
谁杀了她，Ben？
Who killed Jocie, Ben?
告诉我，我想知道
Tell me, I've got to know.
玩会儿单人纸牌放松一下吧
How about passing the time
by playing a little solitaire?
好的，现在让我们来解开一些谜团吧
All，right.Now let's start unlocking a few doors.
从侦察队开始
Let's begin with the patrol.
你没有救我们的命也没有消灭一个连的敌人...
You didn't save our lives or take out
an enemy company or anything like that...
对吧，Raymond？
did you, Raymond?
究竟发生了什么事？
What happened?
侦察队被一队苏联空降兵抓住...
The patrol was taken
by a Russian airborne unit...
带上直升飞机...
and flown by helicopter...
穿过满洲里边界，送到了一个叫东华的地方
across the Manchurian border
to a place called Tunghwa.
我们被一队来自莫斯科帕夫洛夫学院...
We were worked on for three days...
的专家训练了三天
by a team of specialists
from the Pavlov Institute in Moscow.
他们研发了一种技术，能够入侵人的潜意识...
They've developed a technique
for descent into the unconscious mind...
- 通过光诱导和药物来实现
- 现在先不管这些
- part light-induced and part drug.
- Never mind all that，not now.
告诉我在东华还发生了什么
Tell me what else happened at Tunghwa.
我们被训练了三天
We were drilled for three days.
我们被要求记住假想行动的所有细节
We were made to memorize
the details of the imaginary action.
还有呢？
What else?
我勒死了Ed Mavole...
And I strangled Ed Mavole...
射杀了Bobby Lembeck
and shot Bobby Lembeck.
一张方块皇后就能有这么好的效果
One red queen works pretty good.
我们看看两张会怎么样，继续玩吧
Let's see what we get with two of them.
Keep playing.
然后我杀了Gaines先生
Then I killed Mr. Gaines.
那只是个测试，我杀谁都无所谓
It was just a test.
It didn't matter who I killed.
他们选了他，来检测我是否服从命令...
They picked him to see
if the linkages worked...
在我被交给美国操控者之前
before they turned me over
to my American operator.
并且跳湖那件事...
And that business
about jumping in the lake...
那确实是我进入催眠模式后干的
it really did happen.
那是个意外
It was an accident.
我在酒吧看到了触发物，碰巧又有人说了类似命令的话
Something somebody said in the bar
accidentally triggered it.
继续玩Keep playing.
然后我杀了Jordan参议员
Then I killed Sen. Jordan.
然后...
And after that...
你听令，忘掉在参议员家发生的所有事
You are to forget everything that
happened at the Senator's house.
明白吗？只有我允许你记起来时，
你才可以记起来
Do you understand? You'll only
remember it when I tell you so.
现在，Raymond，一个重要的问题
Now, Raymond, now the big one.
这一切都是为了什么？
Why is all of this being done?
他们训练你是为了干什么？
What have they built you to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不觉得有人知道...除了
I don't think anybody really
knows except...
莫斯科的Berezovo
Berezovo in Moscow...
还有我的在美国的操控者
and my American operator here.
不管是什么，应该很快会在...
Whatever it is,
it's supposed to happen soon...
大选时发生
right at the convention.
或许...
Maybe...
我不知道
I don't know.
他们可以命令我做任何事，Ben...
They can make me do anything, Ben...
不是吗？
can't they?
任何事
Anything.
走着瞧，孩子
We'll see, kid.
无论他们做什么，都会被我们阻止
We'll see what they can do,
and we'll see what we can do.
所以方块皇后是关键
So the red queen is our baby.
看着他们，孩子
Take a look at this, kid.
52张方块皇后
Fifty-two of them.
好好看着他们，Raymond
Take a good look at them, Raymond.
你看着他们，听我说
And while you're looking, listen.
这是Marco在对你讲话
This is me, Marco, talking.
52张方块皇后和我在对你说话
你知道我们在对你说什么吗？
Fifty-two red queens and me are telling you.
You know what we're telling you?
结束了
It's over.
那些链接，他们那些漂亮的控制你的链接，已经被摧毁了
The links, their beautifully conditioned
links are smashed.
我们说它们被摧毁了，那他们就是被摧毁了
They're smashed as of now,
because we say so.
我们在摧毁链接，撕碎电线
We're busting up the joint,
we're tearing out all the wires.
皇后的所有骑兵和战士...
All the queen's horses
and queen's men...
都不能把那个旧的Raymond拼回来了
will never put old Raymond
back together again.
你再也不用工作了，这是命令
You don't work anymore.
That's an order.
再有任何人邀请你玩单人纸牌...
Anybody invites you to
a game of solitaire...
你就告诉他们，对不起老兄，游戏结束了
you tell them, 'Sorry, buster,
the ball game is over.'
我的美国操控者要给我任务了
It's time for my American operator
to give me the plan.
是的，是的，我明白了，母亲
Yes. Yes, I understand, Mother.
她让我立刻去找她
She wants me to go.
楼下有辆车在等我
There's a car waiting
for me downstairs.
晚上九点，大选进入就职演讲环节，
The convention reconvenes at 9:00 p.m.
For the acceptance speeches.
在那之前，我觉得不会有事发生
I don't think anything
will happen until then.
- 我得走了
- 给你个电话号码
- I'd better go now.
- Here is a number.
我手下有500人，如果需要，人数还可以增加到1000
I've got 500 people at my disposal,
a thousand if I need them.
打这个电话找我...
尽量在8:30之前打...
You call me at that number.
Try to call me by 8:30...
或者你尽快搞清楚他们要干什么，打给我
or as soon as you find out
whatever it is they want you to do.
记住，Raymond，电线已经拔掉了
Remember, Raymond,
the wires have been pulled.
他们没法儿再控制你了
They can't touch you anymore.
你自由了
You're free.
我决定让你穿牧师的衣服...
It's been decided that you will be
dressed as a priest...
以便你在之后的混乱中脱身
to help you get away
in the pandemonium afterwards.
春锦会给你一支两件式苏联狙击步枪...
Chunjin will give you a two-piece
Soviet Army sniper's rifle...
正好放进一个特制的手提箱里
that fits nicely into a special bag.
那儿有一个不用的打追光用的房间
There's a spotlight booth
that won't be in use.
就在花园第8大道那边的屋顶下
It's up under the roof on the Eighth Avenue
side of the Garden.
你开枪一定要又准又隐蔽
You will have absolutely clear,
protected shooting.
你要开枪打总统候选人的头...
You are to shoot the presidential
nominee through the head...
然后Johnny就会勇敢地站起来...
and Johnny will rise gallantly
to his feet...
扶着Ben Arthur的尸体...
and lift Ben Arthur's body
in his arms...
站在麦克风前开始演说
and stand in front of the microphones
and begin to speak.
演说很短...
The speech is short...
但那是我听过的最鼓舞人心的演说
but it's the most rousing speech
I've ever read.
这项工作已经在这里和苏联断断续续地进行了八年了
It's been worked on here and in Russia,
on and off, for over eight years.
我会让人从他手里把尸体带走
I shall force someone
to take the body away from him.
然后Johnny会吸引所有的麦克风和摄像机...
Then Johnny will really hit those
microphones and those cameras...
身上沾满Arthur的鲜血...
with blood all over him...
拉开所有试图帮他的人...
fighting off anyone who tries
to help him...
保卫美国，
即使这意味着Johnny牺牲他自己的生命
Defending America,
even if it means his own death.
这会让全国的电视观众陷入疯狂...
Rallying a nation of television viewers
into hysteria...
把我们送进白宫...
to sweep us up into the White House...
我们会手握大权，把军事管制变成彻头彻尾的混乱
with powers that will make martial law
seem like anarchy.
Now this is very important...
好好听着接下来的话...
I want the nominee to be dead...
我想要候选人在开始演讲两分钟后死去...
I want the nominee to be dead about two minutes after
he begins his acceptance speech...
由于他讲话的速度有变化
depending on his reading time
under pressure.
他一说完以下句子，你就开枪，
You are to hit him right at the point
that he finishes the phrase
我不会要求任何一个美国同胞
'Nor would I ask of any fellow
American... '
起来保卫自己的自由
'in defense of his freedom... '
但我会起来保卫每个人的自由
'that which I would not
gladly give myself.'
我把我的生命献给自由的美国
'My life before my liberty.'
听清楚了吗？
Is that absolutely clear?
能给我重复一遍吗？Raymond？
Would you repeat it for me, Raymond?
我不会要求任何一个美国同胞
'Nor would I ask of any fellow American... '
起来保卫自己的自由
'in defense of his freedom... '
但我会起来保卫每个人的...
'that which I would not
gladly give... '
自由
'myself.'
我把我的生命献给自由的美国
'My life before my liberty.'
我知道你永远也不会理解这一切，Raymond...
I know you will never entirely
comprehend this, Raymond...
但你得相信我，我不知道会是你被催眠
but you must believe
I did not know it would be you.
我为他们工作，为他们而战
I served them.
I fought for them.
我正在为他们赢取...
I'm on the point of
inning for them...
打败美国的最好机会
the greatest foothold
they will ever have in this country.
他们却如此回报我，把你的灵魂带走，
给我一具空壳
And they paid me back
by taking your soul away from you.
我跟他们说过，帮我训练一个刺客
I told them to build me
an assassin.
我想要一个来自杀手世界的杀手，然后他们选择了你...
I wanted a killer from a world
filled with killers, and they chose you...
因为他们觉得这样，会让我和他们的关系更紧密
because they thought it would bind me
closer to them.
现在，一切都要结束了
But now we have come
almost to the end.
只剩最后一步...
One last step...
当我得到权力，我就会让他们...
and when I take power they will be
pulled down and ground into dirt...
为在你身上做的一切...
for what they did to you...
为轻蔑地低估我，付出代价
and what they did in so contemptuously
underestimating me.
测试，1,2,3,4,5,6
Test.One, two, three, four, five, six.
我们需要灯光，开灯
We need the lights. Lights.
关灯
Lights out.
他为什么还没打来？
Why hasn't he called?
这是预料之中的风险，Ben，
你当时做的对
It was a calculated risk, Ben.
You were right to take it.
虽然这不是真的，但我很高兴你能这么说
Even if it's not true,
it's nice of you to say it.
- 花园里全是人
- 别紧张
- The Garden's filling up.
- Take it easy.
- 8:44了
- 我知道
- 8:44.
- I know.
如果Steinkamp还不把那顶傻乎乎的帽子摘了...
If Steinkamp doesn't take off
that stupid hat...
赶紧去干活儿，我就把他降到一等兵
and stop messing around with
those broads, I'll bust him into a PFC.
放松，Ben
Easy, Ben.
好吧，Milt，我搞砸了！是我搞砸了！
Okay, Milt, I blew it! I blew it！
我想那个的戏法比你的强，应该用我的，
My magic is better than your magic.
我早就该知道的，情报工作者，
I should've known better.
Intelligence Officer.
应该叫我傻瓜情报工作者
Stupidity Officer is better.
如果五角大楼想开设一个傻瓜部门...
If the Pentagon wants to open up
a stupidity division...
我应该去当头儿
they know who they can get
to lead it.
Raymond是他们的，他是他们的，并且永远
都是他们的
Raymond was theirs, he is theirs,
and he'll always be theirs.
还有时间，他还有可能打来
There's time.
He may still call.
为了钱吗？
For money?
我是这么想的
That's what I figured.
- 咱们走吧
- 好的，Ben，咱们走
- Let's get the hell out of here.
- All right, Ben, let's go.
Milt,你得阻止这个集会！
Milt,you've got to stop this thing.
我怎么阻止？用什么理由？
How can I stop it?
On what evidence?
如果这儿有个炸弹，或者你收到线报说这儿有炸弹，
你一定会阻止这个集会的，
If there was a bomb here,
or you got a tip there was, you'd stop it.
即使是要清空白宫里的人，你也一定会这么干的
You'd empty the White House,
if you had to.
我跟你说，这儿有个定时炸弹，正在倒计时
I tell yuo there's a time bomb here,
just waiting to go off.
女士们先生们，现在奏国歌
Ladies and gentlemen,
our national anthem
别抽了，Raymond从来没失过手
Stop twitching，Raymond has never missed
with a rifle in his life.
我们就要成功了，亲爱的
We're in like Flynn, lover.
- 女士们先生们
- 放松就好
- Ladies and gentlemen...
- Just take it easy.
让我们欢迎，下一任美国总统！
I give you the next President
of the United States！
主席先生...
Mr. Chairman...
代表们，我的美国同胞们...
delegates, my fellow Americans...
这是一份需要极大的谦卑...
It is with great humility...
带着高度自豪的工作...
albeit with enormous pride...
我觉得，必须要有人来干这份工作...
and with a sense of the job to be done...
那么我就带着谦卑与感激之心...
that I most humbly and most gratefully...
接受提名，成为国家最高领导人
accept this nomination
for the highest office in our land
我们都充分地意识到
It is with a full awareness
摆在我们国家面前的这四年
that the four years
that lie ahead for this country
从某种意义上来说，是决定性的四年
are, in a sense, the crucial years.
按照Churchill先生的一句话来说...
The years, if I may borrow
Mr. Churchill's phrase...
是具有决定意义的四年
'the years of decision.'
按照我的话来说，
And, if I may be
permitted a phrase of my own
这是要努力奋斗的四年！
the years of striving!
过去做过什么...
For it is not what has been done...
不重要...
in the past...
遥远的未来会做些什么...
nor what may be done
against the far horizons...
也不重要...
of some distant future...
重要的是我们现在要做的！
but what will be done now！
我不会要求任何一个美国同胞
Nor would I ask of any fellow American
起来保卫自己的自由
in defense of his freedom...
但我会起来保卫每个人的自由
...that which I would notgladly give myself.
我把我的生命献给自由的美国！
My life before my liberty!
你无法阻止他们，军队也无法阻止他们，
所以我必须阻止他们
You couldn't have stopped them, the army
couldn't have stopped them, so I had to.
这就是为什么我不给你打电话
That's why I didn't call.
可怜的，无依无靠的，没有朋友的Raymond
Poor friendless,
friendless Raymond.
他死时还戴着他的勋章
He was wearing his medal
when he died.
有时应该读读这些嘉奖状
You should read
some of the citations sometime.
好好读读它们
Just read them.
救出八位囚犯，行动中击毙四个敌人...
'Taken, eight prisoners,
killing four enemy in the process... '
当时他的一条腿和一条手臂已经断了
'while one leg and one arm
were shattered.'
他只能在地上爬，因为另一条腿也炸没了
'He could only crawl, because
the other leg had been blown off.'
Edwards
'Edwards.'
负伤五次
'Wounded five times.'
拉着23位烈士的尸体，和手下71人中仅存的两位伤员
'Dragged himself across the direct fire
of three enemy machine guns... '
穿过敌人三架机关枪的火力网...
'to pull two of his 71 wounded men
to safety amid dead... '
来到安全地带，Holderman
'and 23 casualties. Holderman
他被敌人派来毁灭我们...
'Made to commit acts...
这个事件是机密，我不能讲出具体内容...
'too unspeakable to be cited here...
敌人夺去了他的思想和灵魂
'by an enemy who had captured
his mind and his soul.
他最终解放了自己...
'He freed himself at last...
并且，在最后关头...
'and in the end...
英勇地，毫不迟疑地献出了他的生命...
'heroically and unhesitatingly
gave his life...
拯救了他的国家
'to save his country.
Raymond Shaw
'Raymond Shaw.'
操！还有多少？
Hell! Hell!
Ripped from DVD by: IronMan_br